<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repository on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://vanilla.github.io/docs/tags/repository/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repository on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://vanilla.github.io/docs/tags/repository/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Repository</title>
      <link>http://vanilla.github.io/docs/help/cloud/repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vanilla.github.io/docs/help/cloud/repo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;private-repository&#34;&gt;Private Repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;http://vanillaforums.com/plans&#34;&gt;VIP plans&lt;/a&gt; come with the option to open a private, shared code repository with the Vanilla Forums team on GitHub. This allows your developers to view and contribute to your custom features and theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your customer success manager will provide you with this repository. Please allow the Vanilla team to organize its structure appropriately and name files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch for production deploys. Anything on that branch should be ready for immediate release. The &lt;code&gt;stage&lt;/code&gt; branch can be periodically deployed to your staging site for testing. Prior to deployments, we merge &lt;code&gt;stage&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;. New features can go on their own &lt;code&gt;feature/x&lt;/code&gt; branches or on a &lt;code&gt;develop&lt;/code&gt; branch for integration testing prior to staging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;accounts&#34;&gt;Accounts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need a GitHub account for each developer that requires access. We strongly suggest limiting the number of developers on your team with direct access to the repository for workflow and communication clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;local-testing&#34;&gt;Local testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to use a local install of Vanilla for testing, please use the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch from our &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/vanillaforums/vanilla&#34;&gt;main repository&lt;/a&gt;. Please follow the installation instruction in the README.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we are not able to provide cloud-exclusive addons for local installation. However, some additional addons may be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/vanillaforums/Addons&#34;&gt;addons repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>