<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="//docs.vanillaforums.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/reporting/</guid>
      <description>What is Reporting? Reporting is a way for members to bring moderators’ attention to content that they believe is inappropriate. “Report” is an option under “Flag” in the Reactions available under each post.
Reporting a post Go to Flag → Report in the Reactions menu at the end of the post. A popup box will prompt you to add a “Reason” both to explain the report and discourage useless reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/</guid>
      <description>What Are Vanilla Analytics? Vanilla comes with analytics allows forum administrators to review vital activity on their forums over a specific time periods.
How to use Vanilla Statistics The Vanilla Statistics plugin is a display layer for the data that is sent to our analytics server. We generate and present you with the statistics in a graphical format for the following:
How to use Vanilla Analytics You can get an overview of your community&amp;rsquo;s analytics by clicking on the &amp;lsquo;Dashboard Site Overview&amp;rsquo; tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/api/</guid>
      <description>API Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s API is documented here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Preview Release</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/api/preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/api/preview/</guid>
      <description>API v2 Overview Vanilla is presenting a preview release of our upcoming API v2. This is a complete rewrite and rearchitecture of our API to be a low-level feature of our platform rather than a wrapper around our existing product.
This preview exposes access to only the most core Vanilla resources:
 Users Roles Discussions Comments Categories Conversations (private messages) Messages (text banners) Tokens (basic API access management)  The full API v2 release will introduce parity with the API v1 feature set, and will trigger the beginning of a long sunset period for that API which we will formally announce at that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes In 2016, VIP releases were every other month. Other customers received updates on an ad-hoc basis.
December  Add full IPv6 support. Add and improve addon icons. Add meta tags for discussion links to generate Twitter cards (when added to tweets). Add settings to Dashboard for category max display depth. Add some padding to HTML tables in posts (improve legibility). Add support for our new CDN. Add accessibility attributes to Customize Theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes Quarterly VIP releases contain all numbered releases within said quarter.
Sometimes bug fixes are backported to the current release, meaning they show up in production earlier than the date noted.
Q2 release 6 (Thursday, June 29)  Improve load time of Vanilla Statistics dashboard summaries. Triple-A theme: Added missing icons for Reactions. Dashboard: Font tweaks for right panel. Dashboard: Fix inaccurate toggle position for embedding URLs in Posting Settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/accessibility/</guid>
      <description>Overview We strive for maximum accessibility in our product design and take defects in it seriously.
&amp;lsquo;508 Compliance&amp;rsquo; refers to a US law that requires that US government websites to be accessible to persons with disabilities (e.g. visual or physical impairment). Accessibility means, among many other things, that a person must be able to use the website with software that reads the website aloud and/or using only a keyboard. Many private companies use the 508 guidelines to ensure websites are accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Badges</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/adding-and-editing-badges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/adding-and-editing-badges/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Disabling badges To disable a badge and prevent it from displaying publicly, click &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; in the badge&amp;rsquo;s row under the &amp;ldquo;Active&amp;rdquo; column. That will toggle it to &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;, indicating it is no longer active. Inactive badges remain awarded to any users that received it previously. You can re-enable them by clicking &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;, which will then toggle back to &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;, indicating it is active again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Ranks</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/adding-and-editing-ranks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/adding-and-editing-ranks/</guid>
      <description>Adding a Ranks Go to the &amp;ldquo;Ranks&amp;rdquo; page of the Dashboard and click the &amp;ldquo;Add Rank&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom of the list.
Editing a Rank On the &amp;ldquo;Ranks&amp;rdquo; page, click the &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;rdquo; button next to the Rank you wish to modify.
Rank information Name &amp;amp; Label The name of the rank is how it is referred to. Users will see it in the notification they receive when they attain the rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Reactions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/adding-and-editing-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/adding-and-editing-reactions/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Selecting Reactions Vanilla comes with a wide range of reactions in your Dashboard, of which a few are enabled by default. You can toggle them on or off depending on what reactions are appropriate to your community. To enable or disable a reaction on your forum, click the &amp;ldquo;Active/Inactive&amp;rdquo; toggle next to each reaction in the Dashboard under &amp;ldquo;Reactions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing User Notes</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/adding-and-editing-user-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/adding-and-editing-user-notes/</guid>
      <description>Adding a Note To add a note for a user go to their profile. In their edit profile drop down there should be an item called Add Note. Users must have the permission Garden.Moderation.Manage or Moderation.UserNotes.Add (if present) to add notes.
Viewing Notes To view a user’s notes go to their profile. There will be a notes link on the side panel. Note that both notes and warnings are displayed in the same list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addons</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/</guid>
      <description>What Are Addons? Addons are like apps for your forum. They can be enabled or disabled from your Dashboard. Each one can add one or more features, or modify how an existing feature works. You can tailor your users&amp;rsquo; experience to the needs of your community by carefully selecting addons.
Vanilla is structured such that its baseline installation only contains features that we feel are essential to every community. Addons let you flavor Vanilla to the specific needs of the community you are building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Analytics</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/advanced-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/advanced-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Analytics Overview Available on certain plans as an add-on, Advanced Analytics give you further insights into your community.
 Metrics: Metrics a single number that quantify something for the selected time range. Leaderboards: Leaderboards are tables showing the ranking of specific items for the selected time range. The &amp;ldquo;previous&amp;rdquo; rankings are calculated using the rankings of the previous time range. Graphs: Graphs can come in multiple forms! Line, Area, Pie chart and Bar graphs use the selected time range to group the fetched information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Embedding</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/embedding/advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/embedding/advanced/</guid>
      <description>Overview The advanced embedding technique is for developers who require programmatic interaction between the Vanilla iframe and their parent window. It employs easyXDM and a special container layer to achieve this. It requires a more in-depth setup than Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s basic embed solution.
Setting Up Advanced Embedding Enable forum embedding via the Dashboard. Then set Garden.Embed.Allow to 2 in your config. Cloud customers will have this done by support staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Search</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/advanced-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/advanced-search/</guid>
      <description>Overview Advanced Search adds robust options to Vanilla’s native search to help users hunt down specific content within your community. It is available on Corporate level plans and above.
 Better indexing of content The ability to apply filters to searches Auto-complete of results as the user types the search terms  Enabling Advanced Search To enable Advanced Search, you will need to enable the addon and then make a change to your base theme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Settings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/advanced-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/advanced-settings/</guid>
      <description> Advanced Settings The following settings can be configured in the Dashboard under Forum Settings &amp;gt; Advanced:
 Discussions per page (the number of discussions displayed on a page) Comments per page (the number of comments displayed on a page) Editing time limit (this can be used to prevent edits after a certain time period. Some user Roles and permissions will may override this limit) Enable checkboxes (this  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/server-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/server-apache/</guid>
      <description>Apache Pre-requisite You need to have the mod_rewrite module enabled.
Configuration Vanilla includes an .htaccess file for out-of-box Apache support. You may need to edit it, as indicated inside itself, for subfolder usage. Obviously, .htaccess files must be enabled for your web root.
If you are able to, you can also take the content of the .htaccess and use it directly in your main server config file.
Hardening The provided .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearance</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/</guid>
      <description>Customizing Your Forum&amp;rsquo;s Appearance Your community should have a unique look and feel to match your website, app or product. The appearance section of your Dashboard lets you control how your community forum will look.
Site Title and Logo In your Dashboard under Appearance &amp;gt; Banner you can set the following:
 Home page title Site description Banner title (what is displayed in the browser title bar) Banner logo Mobile banner logo Favicon (the small logo that appears on the browser tab) Share image (an image that is sometimes displayed when someone posts a link to your community to a social media site)  Homepage In your Dashboard under Appearance &amp;gt; Homepage you can set the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Ranks over SSO</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/applying-ranks-over-sso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/applying-ranks-over-sso/</guid>
      <description>Applying Ranks over SSO Create a new rank or edit an existing one, checking &amp;ldquo;Applied Manually&amp;rdquo;.
You can now edit a user&amp;rsquo;s profile and select that Rank or apply it over SSO by adding a matching RankID or Rank_Name parameter to the callback.
This only works if you have checked &amp;ldquo;Applied Manually&amp;rdquo; on the rank. Also make sure that no automatically-triggered Ranks have a higher level, or they will override when triggered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assets</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/assets/</guid>
      <description>Assets Assets organize content in a document. Assets are called by the main template (e.g. default.master.tpl) which renders the content currently stored in them. Assets are managed with code via plugins or the theme hooks file.
Default assets Vanilla uses these assets by default: Head, Content, Panel, and Foot. You cannot rely on every theme having a Panel, which is typically used as a sidebar. The Content asset is required, because it is where the view is rendered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/apiv2/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/apiv2/authentication/</guid>
      <description>The API supports two means of authentication. Both require an access token.
HTTP Header To authenticate with the HTTP header pass you access token in the Authorization field with the bearer scheme.
Authorization: Bearer &amp;lt;your_access_token&amp;gt;  This is the preferred way of authenticating against the API because headers are not usually logged on servers. If you are making server to server calls its worth looking up how to add custom headers in your API client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/authentication/</guid>
      <description>Authenticating API Calls When making calls to the API you&amp;rsquo;ll need to pass an access token in order to authenticate as a user. Vanilla has core support for access tokens, with the following features:
 Access tokens can be issued, verified, and revoked with the AccessTokenModel An access token submitted in the Authorization header will authenticate the appropriate user. Expired access tokens are automatically pruned from the access token table, but stick around for a bit to give appropriate expired errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backend</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/</guid>
      <description>Server Vanilla works with Apache, nginx (our preference) or IIS with proper configuration. The core team does not officially support IIS but accept bug reports and patches related to it. Information and help may be provided on our community forum. We welcome additions to this documentation.
See the dedicated sections for more information about Apache and nginx.
Advanced Handling of Headers To utilize advanced handling of request and networking headers, it is recommended you make the necessary modifications in a bootstrap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Badges</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Purpose Badges are designed to reinforce desirable behaviors on a forum. They are not necessarily awards for the best or most of something, but rather signs that point the way to positive participation in a community.
Default badges Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s Badges addon automatically creates a wide variety of badges. Some relate to core forum functions (like commenting), and some are only triggered by using additional addons (like Reactions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Settings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/banner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/banner/</guid>
      <description>Banner Settings On the Banner Settings page you can control the following aspects of your forum:
 Homepage title: This is the title displayed on your home page. This title will also appear in search engines. Site Description: This is the site description for your homepage. Other pages will have description generated by the content. Banner Title: This is the title will in your community&amp;rsquo;s banner, if you have not uploaded a banner image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building new porters</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/build/</guid>
      <description> Building a new porter file We don&amp;rsquo;t support your forum? Here are some tips for getting started rolling your own.
 Copy an existing class, like class.smf.php and rename it. Start simple. Get a working porter for users, categories, discussions, and comments before expanding its scope.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/css/</guid>
      <description>Theming with CSS Theming Hosted Vanilla You can overide any theming you want in the customize theme section in your Vanilla dashboard. Apply any CSS you feel is appropriate to override the current theme. If you are looking to learn more about customizing CSS in our hosted product, check out theme tips on our blog.
Adding additional CSS To add additional CSS to the existing base Vanilla CSS file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancellation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  The Worst Day Hey, it happens. On rare occassion, we need to go our separate ways. We hate to see any customer leave, but it&amp;rsquo;s important any cloud providers you use have a strong data ownership policy. Ours is pretty simple: It&amp;rsquo;s your data.
Getting your data There are four custom components to any forum:
 Database Uploaded files (avatars, images, etc) Theme or plugin done as a customer-specific customization Config  Of these, the only one we do not ever provide is the config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/categories/</guid>
      <description>What Are Categories Categories are how Vanilla organizes discussions within a community. Categories can be added, edited, deleted, sorted, and tiered via the Dashboard. Every discussion is placed in one (and only one) category. You can find Categories under the Settings tab Dashboard, listed under “Forum Settings”. You can access it directly by going to /vanilla/settings/categories.
At the top of the page, you will presented with the option to either add a new category, or disable them completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Log</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/changelog/</guid>
      <description>Version Change Log This is for packaged, gold releases of the self-hosted product. We publish beta and release candidate change logs on the forum. We provide separate cloud release notes since they are scheduled differently.
Vanilla numbers major releases with the first decimal place. A second decimal indicates a minor patch release.
2.3 Released 18 Nov 2016
2.2.1 Released 7 May 2016
2.2 Released 12 Nov 2015
2.1.13 Released 29 Oct 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Repository</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/repository/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Shared Private Repository Our VIP plans come with the option to open a private code repository that you share with the Vanilla Forums team on GitHub. This allows your developers to view and contribute to your custom features and theme.
Setup Your customer success manager will provide you with this repository. Please allow the Vanilla team to organize its structure appropriately and name files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/conduct/</guid>
      <description>Code of Conduct Adapted from Swift&amp;rsquo;s Code of Conduct v1.3 for now because a copied code is better than no code.
As contributors and maintainers of this project, and in the interest of fostering an open and welcoming community, we pledge to respect all people who contribute through reporting issues, posting feature requests, updating documentation, submitting pull requests or patches, and other activities.
We are committed to making participation in this project a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of level of experience, gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, personal appearance, body size, race, ethnicity, age, religion, or nationality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Standard</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/coding-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/coding-standard/</guid>
      <description>Standards As of May 2014, Vanilla will adhere to PSR-2 with a few exceptions. We have been mass-updating our source code as possible without breaking backwards compatibility (most notably by refraining from changing the casing of existing variables).
We&amp;rsquo;ve named our primary exception to PSR-2 the Lord Brackos rule - Same-line open braces on all classes, method, and function definitions.
We adopted this standard for all the usual reasons: our team is growing, and we want to make sure things stay consistent between our various projects, and it&amp;rsquo;s annoying and hard to read when everything is styled differently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/community/</guid>
      <description>Developers Community We have a vibrant developers&amp;rsquo; community. Please register there to ask general questions, contribute feedback and ideas, help others, add your own plugins &amp;amp; themes to the official directory, and sign the contributors&amp;rsquo; agreement.
Get Notified Want to get notified about the newest releases?
 Sign up for the VanillaForums.org newsletter in your community profile. Watch the RSS feed for the &amp;lsquo;blog&amp;rsquo; category. Follow our Twitter account.  Plugins These addons are currently used on our community forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla configuration files Vanilla uses a file-based configuration system.
Vanilla is distributed with a file at /conf/config-defaults.php which we will call &amp;ldquo;config-defaults&amp;rdquo;. After installation, a file is created at /conf/config.php which we will call simply &amp;ldquo;config&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;config.php&amp;rdquo;.
Your config-defaults file should never be edited. It is overwritten during every upgrade. Sometimes future changes may depend on your default configuration being changed and this is the mechanism thru which it will happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/</guid>
      <description>How to Contribute General  Welcome folks to the community and be awesome! Answer questions. Report issues like a pro (see below). Triage issues already reported! Test pre-releases. Contribute docs. Help translate Vanilla. Evaluate community addons &amp;amp; offer feedback. Do accessibility testing! Unplug your mouse, turn on a screen reader, and see what it&amp;rsquo;s like to use Vanilla.  Developers  Contribute code via pull requests (requires Contributor Agreement) Contribute addons &amp;amp; themes to the Official Directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controllers &amp; URLs</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/controllers/</guid>
      <description>Controllers In our MVC context, controllers are the traffic cops. They receive a parsed request (typically the URL in the address bar), build some data using models, and send it back to the browser in a view.
Dispatcher Vanilla maps URLs to controllers in a fairly direct way. The Dispatcher (Gdn_Dispatcher) receives incoming requests and invokes the appropriate controller(s).
Mapping URLs First it looks for an application name, then a controller name, then a method name, then any arguments which will be passed in the order given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curating with Reactions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/curating-with-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/curating-with-reactions/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Curating with Reactions Reactions can provide your community with powerful self-curation tools. It&amp;rsquo;s very important to understand your community (or the community you intend to build) before selecting what reactions to use.
Any of the thresholds or increment values mentioned in this document can be modified via support.
Promoting content Promote is a special reaction. Only users with the &amp;ldquo;Curation&amp;rdquo; permission (or that ability via Ranks) are able to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Domain</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/getting-started/custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/getting-started/custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>Custom Domain for Your Forum Community Instead of having your community url look like this: mysite.vanillacommunity.com, it can look like this: mysite.com or community.mysite.com. It’s a simple, two-step process that we recommend for all new forum owners. Please note that you must purchase or create your desired url from a domain registrar before customizing your Vanilla Forums domain.
Setup  Log in to the domain name registrar where your domain is hosted (ex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Theme</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/custom-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/custom-theme/</guid>
      <description> Customize Theme Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s base theme HTML can be modified and CSS can be overriden. In order to modify a Vanilla theme, you must posses good knowledge of HTML and CSS. Please consult the Vanilla Forums Theme Guide for detailed theming instructions.
Additional Resources:
 Vanilla Forums Theme Guide Vanilla Blog: Theme Tips Video: Theming Vanilla Forums  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard The Administration Panel, known as the Dashboard, provides access to the control features of your Vanilla Forum. Each Administration Panel is presented in sections, the header, the main navigation, the work area, and the footer. The top portion of all Panels, the header, is featured in a dark blue gradient. The header shows the name of your forum as a link to your forum&amp;rsquo;s main page, a profile link (shown as your user name), and Sign Out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data privacy</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/data-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/data-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Types of Information Vanilla makes distinctions about what user information is public vs. personal, and we deal with these types of information in different ways. This is a technical document to avoid privacy issues when configuring your forum or writing a plugin.
Public user info We consider usernames and user IDs (User.Name and User.UserID) to be public information. This data is used in URLs, embedded in page data, and generally available to any user with basic permission to view or access your forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database access</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/database/</guid>
      <description>Database layer Vanilla only supports MySQL. It has a generic SQL driver implementation built on top of PDO to potentially allow for other databases (which you can see in /library/databases). However, at this time, the Vanilla team has no plans to support additional databases.
The best way to access the database is via existing models. For instance, to get a list of discussions, use the Get method in the DiscussionModel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/datasets/</guid>
      <description>Datasets The Gdn_Dataset object is a way to store data. Most of the time, this data is the result of a query to the database. When you use our database object (as you always should) to execute a database select query, it will return a dataset.
Here are a few commonly used methods you&amp;rsquo;ll want to know about:
 count() returns the number of records in the dataset. firstRow() returns the first record in the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Support</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/developer-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/developer-support/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Developer Support VIP plans include developer support, offered for a fixed period of time for a fixed number of individuals in your organization. During that time, those folks can reach out directly to Vanilla developers for advanced assistance in setting up embedding, single sign-on, theming, and appropriate addons &amp;amp; settings.
We will continue to assist you with our outstanding professional support even after your developer support ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Tools</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/tools/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla uses a wide range to tools and technologies to build its product. This list is simply to guide new developers getting acclimated to our ecosystem. All our developers use MacOS.
Stacks Supported  PHP 5.6 - 7.1 (as of Vanilla 2.5) Unix, Windows, or OSX nginx, Apache, or IIS MySQL, Percona, or MariaDB  Cloud Stack  PHP 7.1 nginx Percona Varnish memcached Zend OPcache Sphinx OpenStack  Developer Tools  homebrew git xdebug PHPUnit Composer Hub CodeSniffer Phing Travis CI Scrutinizer  Frontend Build  Sass SCSS-Lint Yarn Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developers</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! The Developers section is primarily targeted at folks using the open source product who have at least a basic understanding of PHP, HTML, CSS and Javascript.
Clients of VanillaForums.com (cloud) should contact support to address technical issues. Our hosted product does not allow direct file access to ensure security and performance, which precludes many instructions in this section.
Security Issues and Responsible Disclosure Found a security issue? Please contact us at support@vanillaforums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/email/</guid>
      <description>Sending Emails The Garden framework includes an Email object for sending and configuring emails. The formatting of Vanilla Emails is handled by the EmailTemplate property of the Email object.
EmailTemplate The EmailTemplate object helps to organize the components of an email and prepare them for output.
These components are:
 Title: A string, placed in a &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; block before the rest of the email text in the default email template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emails</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/emails/</guid>
      <description>Email Appearance You can choose between sending plaintext or HTML emails. The difference is that HTML emails can include colors, images and other styling while plaintext emails are, well, plain text.
HTML emails can be enabled or disabled from the dashboard by navigating to the &amp;lsquo;Email&amp;rsquo; link in the panel. From there, you can also send test emails and configure HTML emails.
HTML Emails You can customize the way your forum&amp;rsquo;s HTML emails look by navigating the &amp;lsquo;Email&amp;rsquo; link in the dashboard&amp;rsquo;s panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedded</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/embed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/embed/</guid>
      <description>Embedding with Seamless jsConnect Part 1 of this documentation told you how to set up jsConnect SSO for site-wide SSO. However, if you have Vanilla embedded in a page you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the SSO doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically sign you in even if users are signed in to the containing page. In order to make the sign in seamless you need to add some SSO information to your embed code.
First, we&amp;rsquo;ll address another important issue: Mobile Safari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/embedding/</guid>
      <description>Embedding Forum Embedding Vanilla Forums works by putting a snippet of code on your website page, and may be a choice if you want to insert your forum into a site quickly. The snippet points to some javascript and the forum is embedded into the page using an iframe
Embedding Checklist
 Choose the embed friendly theme. This theme has minimal padding around it and will look good at any width.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/embedding/</guid>
      <description>Embedding Forum Embedding Vanilla Forums works by putting a snippet of code on your website page, and may be a choice if you want to insert your forum into a site quickly. The snippet points to some javascript and the forum is embedded into the page using an iframe
Embedding Checklist
 Choose the embed friendly theme. This theme has minimal padding around it and will look good at any width.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/emoji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/emoji/</guid>
      <description> Emoji Emoji is a way to express yourself in graphical form in your community. The following are the emoji and the code to use for them to appear.
   Emoji Type Code To Use In Forum     Smileys    &amp;lsquo;smile&amp;rsquo; :smile:   &amp;lsquo;smiley&amp;rsquo; :smiley:   &amp;lsquo;wink&amp;rsquo; :wink:   &amp;lsquo;blush&amp;rsquo; :blush:   &amp;lsquo;neutral&amp;rsquo; :neutral:   &amp;lsquo;relaxed&amp;rsquo; :relaxed:   &amp;lsquo;grin&amp;rsquo; :grin:   &amp;lsquo;joy&amp;rsquo; :joy:   &amp;lsquo;sweat_smile&amp;rsquo; :sweat_smile:   &amp;lsquo;lol&amp;rsquo; :lol:   &amp;lsquo;innocent&amp;rsquo; :innocent:   &amp;lsquo;naughty&amp;rsquo; :naughty:   &amp;lsquo;yum&amp;rsquo; :yum:   &amp;lsquo;relieved&amp;rsquo; :relieved:   &amp;lsquo;love&amp;rsquo; :love:   &amp;lsquo;sunglasses&amp;rsquo; :sunglasses:   &amp;lsquo;smirk&amp;rsquo; :smirk:   &amp;lsquo;expressionless&amp;rsquo; :expressionless:   &amp;lsquo;unamused&amp;rsquo; :unamused:   &amp;lsquo;sweat&amp;rsquo; :sweat:   &amp;lsquo;pensive&amp;rsquo; :pensive:   &amp;lsquo;confused&amp;rsquo; :confused:   &amp;lsquo;confounded&amp;rsquo; :confounded:   &amp;lsquo;kissing&amp;rsquo; :kissing:   &amp;lsquo;kissing_heart&amp;rsquo; :kissing_heart:   &amp;lsquo;kissing_smiling_eyes&amp;rsquo; :kissing_smiling_eyes:   &amp;lsquo;kissing_closed_eyes&amp;rsquo; :kissing_closed_eyes:   &amp;lsquo;tongue&amp;rsquo; :tongue:   &amp;lsquo;disappointed&amp;rsquo; :disappointed:   &amp;lsquo;worried&amp;rsquo; :worried:   &amp;lsquo;angry&amp;rsquo; :angry:   &amp;lsquo;rage&amp;rsquo; :rage:   &amp;lsquo;cry&amp;rsquo; :cry:   &amp;lsquo;persevere&amp;rsquo; :persevere:   &amp;lsquo;triumph&amp;rsquo; :triumph:   &amp;lsquo;frowning&amp;rsquo; :frowning:   &amp;lsquo;anguished&amp;rsquo; :anguished:   &amp;lsquo;fearful&amp;rsquo; :fearful:   &amp;lsquo;weary&amp;rsquo; :weary:   &amp;lsquo;sleepy&amp;rsquo; :sleepy:   &amp;lsquo;tired_face&amp;rsquo; :tired_face:   &amp;lsquo;grimace&amp;rsquo; :grimace:   &amp;lsquo;bawling&amp;rsquo; :bawling:   &amp;lsquo;open_mouth&amp;rsquo; :open_mouth:   &amp;lsquo;hushed&amp;rsquo; :hushed:   &amp;lsquo;cold_sweat&amp;rsquo; :cold_sweat:   &amp;lsquo;scream&amp;rsquo; :scream:   &amp;lsquo;astonished&amp;rsquo; :astonished:   &amp;lsquo;flushed&amp;rsquo; :flushed:   &amp;lsquo;sleeping&amp;rsquo; :sleeping:   &amp;lsquo;dizzy&amp;rsquo; :dizzy:   &amp;lsquo;no_mouth&amp;rsquo; :no_mouth:   &amp;lsquo;mask&amp;rsquo; :mask:   &amp;lsquo;star&amp;rsquo; :star:   &amp;lsquo;cookie&amp;rsquo; :cookie:   &amp;lsquo;warning&amp;rsquo; :warning:   &amp;lsquo;mrgreen&amp;rsquo; :mrgreen:   Love    &amp;lsquo;heart&amp;rsquo; :heart:   &amp;lsquo;heartbreak&amp;rsquo; :heartbreak:   &amp;lsquo;kiss&amp;rsquo; :kiss:   Hand gestures    &amp;rsquo;+1&amp;rsquo; :+1:   &amp;rsquo;-1&amp;rsquo; :-1:   Custom icons    &amp;lsquo;trollface&amp;rsquo; :trollface:    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint: categories</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/categories/</guid>
      <description>/categories/add POST /api/v1/categories/add.ext HTTP/1.1 Host: https://yoursite.vanillaforums.com  Adds a new category.
Authentication: required
Parameters    Parameter Type Description     Name string The name of the category   UrlCode string URL friendly category stub   Description string Description of this category   Sort integer Category sort order rank   ParentCategoryID integer Parent Category (ID, use if no Name)   ParentCategory string Parent Category (Name, use if no ID)   Archived boolean Whether this category is archived   Permissions array Custom permissions for the category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint: comments</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/comments/</guid>
      <description> /comments/add POST /api/v1/comments/add.ext HTTP/1.1 Host: https://yoursite.vanillaforums.com  Creates a new comment.
Authentication: required
Parameters    Parameter Type Description     DiscussionID integer Discussion to post comment to   Body string Comment body   Format string Comment output format   ForeignID string Related foreign content identifier   Type string Comment type    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint: discussions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/discussions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/discussions/</guid>
      <description>/discussions/add POST /api/v1/discussions/add.ext HTTP/1.1 Host: https://yoursite.vanillaforums.com  Creates a new discussion.
Authentication: required
Parameters    Parameter Type Description     Name string Discussion name   Body string Discussion body   Format string Discussion output format   CategoryID integer Discussion Category (ID, use if no Name)   Category string Discussion Category (Name, use if no ID)   ForeignID string Related foreign content identifier   Tags csv List of discussion tags   Type string Discussion type   Closed boolean Discussion closed state   Announce boolean Discussion announced state   Sink boolean Discussion sunk state    /discussions/bookmark POST /api/v1/discussions/bookmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint: multisites</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/multisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/multisites/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Overview The site hub is a special service for VIP customers. It allows you to create sites on your VIP cluster and is used for people that want to integrate communities within their entire organization. You can make hub api calls just like other api calls, but you make those calls against your site hub rather than an individual site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endpoint: roles</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/roles/</guid>
      <description>/roles/add POST /api/v1/roles/add.ext HTTP/1.1 Host: https://yoursite.vanillaforums.com  Add a new role.
Authentication: required
Parameters    Parameter Type Description     Name string The name of the role   Description string Description of this role   Permissions array The permissions of the role. Each global permission is a dot-separated key with a boolean value.   Permissions.Category array Custom category permissions. Each item in the array is a permission for a particular category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment Setup</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/tools/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/tools/environment/</guid>
      <description>After you&amp;rsquo;ve got your tools ready, here&amp;rsquo;s how to set some of them up to work together nicely. We assume you&amp;rsquo;re using MacOS. This is all pretty useless if you&amp;rsquo;re not.
Automate dependency building To automatically recompile Composer dependencies when you make commits, pull, or checkout a different release branch, add this:
#!/bin/sh composer install  To these files in your git repository (creating them if they do not exist):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Hooks</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/hooks/</guid>
      <description>Theming Hooks Themes can be imbued with the power of plugins via a special hooks php file. Using the hooks file, you can override existing functions in Vanilla, plug in to existing Vanilla events, and set data for your views.
To use hooks, create a file named class.themehooks.php in your theme&amp;rsquo;s root directory (/themes/your_theme_name/class.themehooks.php) and edit it there. Hooks files extends Gdn_Plugin, which allows the specification of a setup() method, which is run whenever the theme is enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Facebook Connect allows users to sign in using their Facebook account. You must register your application with Facebook for this plugin to work.
How to set up Facebook Connect In order to set up Facebook Connect, you must create an &amp;ldquo;application&amp;rdquo; in Facebook at: https://developers.facebook.com/apps
Once your application has been set up, you must copy the &amp;ldquo;Application ID&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Application Secret&amp;rdquo; into your Facebook plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forum Merge</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/forum-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/forum-merge/</guid>
      <description>When to Use Forum Merge The ForumMerge plug-in should be used when you want to take one existing Vanilla forum instance and merge it into another existing Vanilla forum. Core Vanilla data, in addition to some plug-in and addon data, will be carried over from the source into the destination forum and reconciled with existing records to avoid conflicts.
What Data is Merged The following Vanilla data will be considered during the merge process:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forum Settings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/</guid>
      <description> Forum Settings In the Forum Settings section of the Dashboard, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to configure the following:
 Create and organize forum Categories Advanced settings, such as setting the number of discussions per page Tagging setup Setting Vanilla to Embed and finding embed code. Configuring Ideation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/</guid>
      <description>Garden&amp;rsquo;s place in Vanilla Vanilla is built on an MVC framework named Garden. Its purpose is to provide an extensible, pluggable platform on which to build all the addons that make Vanilla awesome. The design of its database handling was influenced by CodeIgniter, but its plugin architecture is pretty unique.
Technically, Vanilla is a forum application (addon) built on top of the Garden framework. However, we typically refer to the entire stack as &amp;ldquo;Vanilla&amp;rdquo; for branding consistency and simplicity - including in these docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Welcome to Vanilla! We&amp;rsquo;re glad to have you as a customer (or user!) and we&amp;rsquo;re eager to help make your community a success. This section is designed to give you a jump-start in that direction and is intended for first-time or novice Vanilla administrators.
First Steps If you&amp;rsquo;re launching a new community from scratch, you already know that it can feel like a daunting experience with numerous choices and decisions to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gigya Sign In</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/gigya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/gigya/</guid>
      <description>Gigya Sign In The Gigya Sign In adds the ability to sign to your community with Gigya Social Login. You will need to configure your site in your Gigya dashboard and then set up your login plugin on the Gigya plugins page before you can use the Gigya addon in Vanilla.
Setting up your site in Gigya  Instructions on setting up a a site in Gigya can be found in their site setup documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/github/</guid>
      <description>Github This plugin allows you to submit user discussion and comments as GitHub issues.
Setup Instructions If you already have a Github account, you need to enable API Access for this plugin to work.
 Create a new application in GitHub, and set the callback URL by appending /profile/githubconnect to the end of your forum’s URL. (If your forum is at example.com/forum, your callback URL would be http://example.com/forum/profile/githubconnect). Once your application has been set up, you must copy the ClientID and Secret into your Github plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving and Requesting Badges</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/giving-and-requesting-badges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/giving-and-requesting-badges/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Giving a badge Badges-&amp;gt;Give is the permission that defines who can give badges. By default, moderators and administrators have it.
To manually give a badge to one or more users, click the &amp;ldquo;Give&amp;rdquo; button from the Badges list. Type a username in the provided box. You can give a badge to many users at once by typing all their names, separated by commas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Plus</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/googleplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/googleplus/</guid>
      <description>Google Plus The Google Plus Sign-In adds the ability to sign to your community with Google Plus. You will need to configure your site in Google API Console. This Google+ Video Tutorial also shows you how to set this up.
Setting up social login in Google Plus  Once you have enabled the Google+ Plugin in your Vanilla Dashboard, go to your API Console at Google. You will need to create a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/groups/</guid>
      <description>What are Groups? Groups is an addon for very large communities to allow their users to form their own discussion groups. These groups allows for having discussions outside the normal forum category structure in self-contained areas. Very large communities can be difficult to approach for new users. Groups can be a useful way for users to find other folks with common interests or backgrounds.
Groups have an events list, their own announcements, and leaders who run the show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpers</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/helpers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/helpers/</guid>
      <description>Helper Functions This is a quickstart guide to some of Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s globally available functions and methods. Familiarizing yourself with them will save you time and effort in the long term, and give you clues about how best to use the framework.
This is by no means an exhaustive list, nor full signature documentation. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to find them in the source code (files at /library/core/functions.*.php) for more info.
Getting &amp;amp; setting See functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Settings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/homepage/</guid>
      <description>Homepage The Homepage settings allows you to change the default homepage of your community when they visit your site. By default, Vanilla will use &amp;ldquo;Discussions&amp;rdquo; as your homepage, but you can change it to whatever you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/ideation/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Ideation Ideation gives forum users the ability to upvote and optionally downvote discussions.
Ideas Overview An idea is a discussion that can be voted on by forum users. It has a status that lets moderators easily communicate decisions made on the idea, and determines whether it&amp;rsquo;s open or closed for voting. You can modify, add or delete available statuses from the dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/</guid>
      <description>Importing to Vanilla Already have a community on another platform? Great! We have a tool called Vanilla Porter that can help you migrate from many other popular platforms.
Download Vanilla Porter
Vanilla Porter is a tool that you can upload to your current web server to run in your web browser. It exports any platform to a generic format that the &amp;ldquo;Import&amp;rdquo; option in your new Vanilla Forum can read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inform Messages</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/inform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/inform/</guid>
      <description>Toaster Notifications Inform Messages allow you to let users know of some action that your plugin or application has taken. Inform messages allow you to quickly and easily relay information to users, and handle actions based on interaction with those messages. Use them freely to notify users of saved forms, punishments, rewards, etc.
You can send Inform Messages from within a controller or a plugin, or from a custom javascript function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/installation/</guid>
      <description>Installing Vanilla Our current installation and upgrade instructions are in the README file that comes with Vanilla. If you run into issues, see the Developers &amp;gt; Troubleshooting section of these docs.
Cloud Solution For a 1-click installation hosted plan with professional support and services, see Vanilla Forums Cloud Hosting plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrations</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/</guid>
      <description>Integrations Vanilla integrates with several third party applications, including:
 Salesforce Zendesk GitHub Wordpress Akismet WithList MailChimp Social logins (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.)  Vanilla also supports integration through an API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internationalization &amp; Localization</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/i18n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/i18n/</guid>
      <description> Adding translatable phrases to Vanilla Considerations for adding phrases to Vanilla or your addon:
 Default to English. Use the t() for all user-viewed text. Never use t() for HTML classes or other frontend code. Always use a succinct definition string. Avoid jargon or regional dialect.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/linkedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/linkedin/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn Linked In social sign in allows users to sign in using their LinkedIn account. You must register your application with LinkedIn for this addon to work.
How to Set up LinkedIn Social Sign in  Go to the LinkedIn Developer Network at https://www.linkedin.com/secure/developer/ Click Add New Application. When you create the application, you can choose what to enter in most fields, but you have to make sure you enter specific information for some fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locales</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/locales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/locales/</guid>
      <description>Translating Vanilla Want to help us improve our translations? We have a Transifex project for contributing to this. Create an account there and submit your improvements.
Need to customize the phrasing just on your site in particular? See &amp;ldquo;Overriding locales&amp;rdquo; below.
Translation tips Want to help translate? Awesome! Here are some tips for creating great translations.
 Please make sure that your changes use generic terminology and good grammar that can apply to all forums and avoids interest- or region-specific terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/logging/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Advanced logging Additional logging is available on our highest-tier plans for an additional fee to cover the additional load &amp;amp; performance hit incurred by more verbose logs.
The logs are available via a Dashboard page under &amp;ldquo;Event Log&amp;rdquo;. They can be filtered by date range, event name, and severity. Sorting is chronological or reverse-chronological.
Events We are currently able to log the following additional events for auditing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MailChimp Push</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/mailchimp-push/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/mailchimp-push/</guid>
      <description>Overview MailChimp is one of the world’s leading email marketing platforms, allowing it’s users to send newsletters, automated messages, and set up targeted campaigns to help their business.
Our plugin synchronizes the email addresses of your community’s users with a designated mailing list. As your community grows, or users change their email address, Vanilla will send notifications to MailChimp to update the specified list.
Enabling MailChimp Push MailChimp Push is a feature provided at every plan level, it can be activated for your forum through a support request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Groups</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/groups/managing-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/groups/managing-groups/</guid>
      <description>Adding your first groups After enabling the Groups addon, &amp;ldquo;Groups&amp;rdquo; will appear in your top-level navigation. In a customized theme, this may not be the case and you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go directly to the URL &amp;ldquo;/groups&amp;rdquo; from your forum domain (e.g. &amp;ldquo;yoursite.vanillaforums.com/groups&amp;rdquo;).
As the administrator, click the &amp;ldquo;New Group&amp;rdquo; button near the top of the page. The &amp;ldquo;Icon&amp;rdquo; image shows on the groups lists. The &amp;ldquo;Banner&amp;rdquo; is the large image at the top of your group&amp;rsquo;s page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messages</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/message/</guid>
      <description>Messages Messages can appear anywhere in your community, and can be used to inform your users of news and events.
Configuring Messages Messages can be added to your forum by clicking on the Add Message button when on the Message page, and choosing the following Message options:
 You can determine on which page a Message will seen, for example just on the profile page. You can add a Message to a specific category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/migration/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Overview Vanilla offers full, professional migration services from nearly any platform imaginable. If you provide the data, we&amp;rsquo;ll figure out how to make it work in Vanilla.
The process below assumes you will provide a database dump. We also perform API-based migrations from cloud services when that is necessary and possible. Talk to your account representative if you require a different type of migration like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Models, Forms, &amp; Validation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/models/</guid>
      <description>Models Datasets Controllers Views
The theory of a Model in MVC is that it is an object representation of the data being manipulated. In Garden, however, the actual object representation of the data comes from the DataSet class in the form of a php stdClass. So, as you may have guessed already, in Garden the model isn’t a representation of the data. In Garden, a model relates directly to a table, and (with the help of the database object) allows you to retrieve information from the table, enforce the schema of that table on the data being manipulated, and put data into the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moderation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/</guid>
      <description>Moderation Overview Vanilla tries to make moderation easy by giving you access to many moderation features through the public UI and by inviting members to participate in reporting abuse.
Managing Users In the Dasboard under the Moderation Tab, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to lookup users. Clicking on the pencil icon will let you edit a user&amp;rsquo;s profile information, appoint roles and perform a password reset.
If the Spoof plugin is turned on, you can also spoof this user, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/modules/</guid>
      <description>If controller methods represent the main content/purpose of a page, modules represent secondary information or functions. Modules are small groupings of functionality or information on a page. Some modules that are bundled with Garden include:
 HeadModule - Allows addition of javascript, css &amp;amp; meta information to be rendered in the page. MenuModule - Handles management and rendering of items in the main menu. PagerModule - Takes information about a dataset and renders a pagelist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Multisite management Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s cloud solution offers a number of configuration settings for enterprise-grade deployments.
Deployment Types Single Community This is a classic forum setup. It is the equivalent of 1 installation of forum software. It can have any number of categories (what other products call “topic areas” or “forums/subforums”) arranged in a hierarchy. Each Single Community needs a domain or subdomain assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite Sync</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/sync/</guid>
      <description>Hub Sync A number of settings can be synced between the hub and its nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notifications</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/notifications/</guid>
      <description>Overview Notifications for certain forum events can be delivered in-app (via Growl-style popups) and/or via email. New users will be opted in to a list of notifications that can be configured by the administrator. Users may edit these preferences in their profile at any time.
Any notification level may be selectively disabled globally. It is also possible to globally disable all email sending by setting Garden.Email = false in your config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/oauth/</guid>
      <description>SSO with OAuth: Overview Vanilla currently provides OAuth2 integrations with these third-party services as ready-to-go addons:
 Facebook Twitter LinkedIn Google+  Because OAuth 2.0 is an SSO framework and not a narrowly defined protocol (see OAuth 2.0 Spec), custom services work is typically required to set up an OAuth solution for your forum. In an attempt to minimize the amount of custom services required to create SSO integrations, Vanilla has created a base class that can easily be extended by custom plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/oauth/</guid>
      <description>SSO with OAuth: Overview Vanilla currently provides OAuth2 integrations with these third-party services as ready-to-go addons:
 Facebook Twitter LinkedIn Google+  Because OAuth 2.0 is an SSO framework and not a narrowly defined protocol (see OAuth 2.0 Spec), custom services work is typically required to set up an OAuth solution for your forum. In an attempt to minimize the amount of custom services required to create SSO integrations, Vanilla has created a base class that can easily be extended by custom plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Links</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/page-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/page-links/</guid>
      <description>Page Links We&amp;rsquo;ve created dedicated Smarty functions for a number of links to Vanilla pages that make it easier to build your forum&amp;rsquo;s navigation.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic syntax, where * is the link type.
{*_link wrap=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; format=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    wrap  string  li  The tag to wrap the link in.  text  string  varies  What the text for the link should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permissions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/permissions/</guid>
      <description>Permissions Overview Vanilla uses permissions to restrict access to particular content, options, or workflows. There are a number of functions built into the framework to do this efficiently. We eschew role-detection as a means of access control.
For example, we would never check to make sure someone was in a role named Moderator before granting access to an option, we would check a permission like Garden.Moderation.Manage.
Naming Permissions We use the same dot notation syntax for permissions as we do for config settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Quickstart</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/plugins/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/plugins/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Quickstart Links  Read about our hooks system: Extending Vanilla with plugins Download the official Example plugin Download other plugins from the Addon Directory and borrow their code. Get help in the developer community  Quickstart Guide Vanilla is built on an object-oriented, MVC framework. If you&amp;rsquo;re coming at this from a mostly function-based world like WordPress or Drupal, this might read like moonspeak. That&amp;rsquo;s OK! Soak it up and ask questions on the forum after you follow this guide and play with the examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugins</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/plugins/</guid>
      <description>Extending Vanilla with plugins Vanilla is a very customizable, flexible platform because there are many ways to hook into it without ever modifying its code.
Events &amp;amp; Handlers Any class that extends the class &amp;ldquo;Pluggable&amp;rdquo; has the ability to call
$this-&amp;gt;fireEvent(&#39;EventName&#39;);  and then plugins can attach to that event to perform an action.
There is a PluginManager that detects any enabled plugins. When the FireEvent method is called, it pings the PluginManager class to see if there are any plugins that want to attach to the event name being fired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pockets</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/pockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/pockets/</guid>
      <description>Overview Pockets add areas to your forum where you can inject custom HTML or Javascript into your theme. It is a powerful tool that makes Vanilla flexible for ad placement, google analytics, and other small customizations.
Pockets are designed to be used by advanced users and developers who can write and review their own code.
Setup Pockets are available on all plan levels. To activate it, simply locate it in your addon list (/dashboard/settings/addons) and toggle it on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/</guid>
      <description>Overview &amp;ldquo;Posting&amp;rdquo; or commenting on a discussion is the primary way users will interact with your community. There is a range of discussion types, helping communities adjust the functionality to suit their needs.
At the bottom of each discussion, the user will encounter a text field:
Users are able to type their comments here and submit them by hitting the “Post Comment” button. That comment will immediately append the bottom of the discussion, adding it to the conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premium Services</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Cloud Services Overview This section details services and processes that are only offered on certain plan levels. It includes workflows between Vanilla Forums and our clients, suggestions for getting the most out of your services, and expectations for how services will be delivered and communicated.
If you are a cloud client and have any questions, please contact support, your account representative, or your customer success manager if one has been assigned to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Community</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/roles-permissions/private-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/roles-permissions/private-community/</guid>
      <description>Making your Community Private If you set your community to private, only registered members will be able to view and post. If a user that is not logged in browses to the community, they will see a login page.
To make your community private:
 Go to the Addons page in the Dashboard Turn on the &amp;lsquo;Private Community&amp;rsquo; addon Click on the addon settings, this will take you to the Roles and Permission page Turn on &amp;lsquo;Enable Private Communities&amp;rsquo;  Additional Resources:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pull Requests</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/pull-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/contributing/pull-requests/</guid>
      <description>Using pull requests to contribute code We love pull requests! They&amp;rsquo;re the core of our workflow.
All code is added to Vanilla via pull requests (PRs). A pull request is simply a request to merge code from a particular branch into another (usually a feature or hotfix branch into master). GitHub&amp;rsquo;s pull request feature tracks discussion, labels, assignments, and changes over time to a pull request.
Creating a pull request  Branch from master and checkout that branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/qna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/qna/</guid>
      <description>Overview Vanilla supports question and answer type discussions. Q&amp;amp;A discussions differ in the following ways:
 When a question is answered, the member who asked the question will receive a notification and will be prompted to indicate if the answer answered the question or not.
 Valid answers are highlighted and displayed at the top of the discussion list. Members who answer questions will receive badges (if badges are turned on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla Forums Cloud Customers, check out our Ultimate Vanilla Forums Theme Guide.
With Vanilla, you have full control over both the CSS and the actual HTML of every page in every application. The easiest thing for most designers is to just alter the CSS, so we&amp;rsquo;ll start there:
Part 1: CSS &amp;amp; Design  Copy the /themes/default folder and rename it to your theme name so it sits in the root theme folder like this: /themes/your_theme_name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranks</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/</guid>
      <description>What is a Rank? A rank can be assigned to a user to grant or remove certain privileges on your forum. A rank is not Roles &amp;amp; Permissions, which govern content access, moderation abilities, and administrator access.
A user can only have one rank at a time. Typically, the user&amp;rsquo;s rank is displayed on their discussions and comments just after their name. If a user has a Title, that is displayed separately, after their Rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  What are reactions? Reactions are a 1-click response to discussions and comments. Using Reactions enables community members to indicate an emotional (&amp;ldquo;Awesome&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;LOL&amp;rdquo;) or empirical (&amp;ldquo;Agree&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Vote Down&amp;rdquo;) response without typing a comment. This introduces feedback that is otherwise missing from a community when members don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to add to a discussion via a comment. Reactions are available via an addon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirector</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/redirector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/redirector/</guid>
      <description>When to Use Redirector Redirector is a plug-in that translates URLs from many popular forum platforms into Vanilla-friendly URLs. If you&amp;rsquo;re moving from one of the supported platforms, installing and enabling this plug-in will magically handle maintaining the previous platform&amp;rsquo;s links, which can be of tremendous SEO value.
Supported Platforms  IPB Jive phpBB punBB smf vBulletin xenforo  Usage  Install and enable the plug-in. Visit a URL from your previous platform against your Vanilla installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes (Cloud)</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/</guid>
      <description>Cloud release schedule Our customers on VIP plans receive a product update once per quarter with new features, fixes, and enhancements. We coordinate these releases with our customers and provide custom QA or custom scheduling as required.
Customers with a success manager receive updates approximately every other week at a fixed time which is not pre-announced. Other plan levels and all staging sites may receive these updates on an ad-hoc basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requests</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/requests/</guid>
      <description>Requests Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s base Controller class (the class from which all controllers are extended) accepts a DeliveryType parameter on every request. Depending on the type of delivery being requested, a controller in Garden will deliver all of a page, part of a page, or part of a page plus extra information as JSON.
DeliveryType There are four delivery types available:
 DELIVERY_TYPE_ALL: Entire page (default). DELIVERY_TYPE_ASSET: Content for the requested asset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Routing</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/resource-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/resource-routing/</guid>
      <description>RESTful Resource Routing to Controller Methods This section tells you how to name your controller objects and methods so that they can be accessed by API requests. By default, all of your controllers are accessed from the /api/v2/ base path. After that, the rest of the path and the HTTP method determines what method gets called within your app.
Controller Names In order for a controller to be accessible from the API its name must end in &amp;ldquo;ApiController&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roles &amp; Permissions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/roles-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/roles-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Overview Roles and Permissions are used in tandem to control what users can see and do in your community. Upon account creation, there are 6 default Roles in your Vanilla account. Each of the default Roles have permissions that you would expect from the Role name:
 Guest: This is a special role that represents inactive sessions in Vanilla. You can use this role to restrict what logged out users see when viewing your forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routes</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/routes/</guid>
      <description>Routes Route management allows you to create custom urls to specific pages within your Vanilla 2 installation. It also comes with some pre-defined default values.
Pre-defined Routes There are four pre-defined routes that have special meaning. They are: * DefaultController - This is the main page to load when the root url of your Vanilla installation is viewed. * Default404 - The page to view when the requested url could not be found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAML</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/saml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/saml/</guid>
      <description>SSO with SAML: Overview Vanilla has implemented the parts of the SAML 2.0 spec required for SSO. This is done by enabling the SAML SSO addon, and configuring it via its Settings page (Dashboard → Addons → SAML SSO → Settings button).
SAML accounts are mapped to existing forum accounts by email address, or a new account is created if no match is found.
Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s SAML mapping is as follows (the right value is the SAML key):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAML Connection explained</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/saml/connection-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/saml/connection-explained/</guid>
      <description>Creating a new SAML connection When creating a new SAML connection you will need to fill the following fields:
Connection ID This field is the new of your connexion and is used to distinguish it from other potential SSO connexion.
Entity ID The name of your SAML entity. It can be anything but is often the URL of your site.
Site Name A short name for the site. This is displayed on the SSO Sign In button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/seo/</guid>
      <description>Search Engine Optimizations Vanilla subscribes to common sense, vetted principles for improving the findability of your site and its content. We employ no &amp;ldquo;tricks&amp;rdquo; because we believe they ultimately hurt your traffic and reputation.
Curation Having a team dedicated to the curation of your forum is critical to its success. Concisely edited discussion titles, clearly-expressed first posts, and moving discussions to their most-appropriate category are highly effective search engine optimization techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/salesforce/</guid>
      <description>Overview This plugin allows you to:
 Link your Salesforce account to your Vanilla user profile. Create cases and leads from discussions. View leads on Vanilla users profile.  Requirements You must have SSL enabled on your domain. (Your forum must be served over HTTPS)
Setup Configure Application in Salesforce  Log into your Salesforce Account Create new Connected App in Salesforce  Build → Create → Apps → Connected Apps → New Fill the required fields Connected App Name, API Name, Contact Email Enable OAuth Settings Set a Callback URL by appending /profile/salesforceconnect to the end of your forum&amp;rsquo;s URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schemas</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/schemas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/schemas/</guid>
      <description>Schemas Garden\Schema In Vanilla, the Garden\Schema class is used to whitelist parameters for a data structure and validate array of data. It is primarily used for filtering input to API endpoints.
The constructor of Garden\Schema accepts an associative array, describing the expected parameters. The keys of the array define the name of a parameter and its flags (e.g. data type, is required). The values of the array provide a description for each parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seamless Setup</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/seamless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/seamless/</guid>
      <description>Seamless SSO with jsConnect jsConnect uses javascript to allow cross-domain single-signon with another site. We provide several client libraries to help you implement jsConnect on your site. If your site has been programmed in a language that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a client library than this is documentation is for you.
Please note that this is technical documentation and requires knowledge programming to understand.
Functions You&#39;ll Need jsConnect makes use of some functions that are available in most modern programming languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up SSL (https)</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/ssl/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Setting up SSL (https) with Vanilla Cloud Vanilla offers SSL support in Corporate plans and above. In order for us to to enable SSL for your forum, you will need to provide Vanilla with the following:
Certificates start like this: -----BEGIN CERTIFICATE-----  Private keys start like this: -----BEGIN RSA PRIVATE KEY-----   The SSL Certificate for your forum&amp;rsquo;s domain in PEM format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Sign-On (SSO)</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/</guid>
      <description>Single Sign-On overview Single sign-on (SSO) is how to let your users sign on to a third-party system (like a Vanilla Forum) without needing a separate username and password.
In broad terms, an SSO solution defines how two systems securely communicate the identity of a user that is switching between them. In the context of Vanilla, that means the forum securely talking to your site or identity provider to see if a user is signed in, and then automatically using that identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Embed</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/smart-embed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/posting/smart-embed/</guid>
      <description>Smart Embed Vanilla automatically embeds content from many social media sites. When creating a post, simply paste the URL into the editor, like so:
If the URL is from a supported site and has the proper identifier, the content will automatically embed into the post body when published. While some sites offer different types of embed codes, unrecognized parameters may stop Vanilla from correctly parsing the URL. Using the methods below will ensure your content is correctly embedded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart ID</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/smart-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/smart-id/</guid>
      <description>Many API methods take a UserID as one of their required parameters, for example the /badge/give method. Often, especially in a SSO context, the calling system will not know the native Vanilla UserID, but will instead know some other identifying characteristic of the user, such as their Email, Username, or SSO ForeignID.
Fields that accept Smart IDs allow these tokens to be supplied instead of a native UserID. Internally, the Email, Username or SSO ForeignID will be converted into a Vanilla UserID by the API layer and passed along to the core method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarty</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/</guid>
      <description>Smarty Overview Vanilla currently supports both PHP and Smarty views. Smarty is a template engine that allows dynamic content to be inserted into a HTML template using tags. These tags are wrapped in curly braces: {tag}, and can represent variables or the output of a function call. They are replaced when the page is rendered. The default master view in Vanilla is a smarty template. See it in action by navigating to /applications/dashboard/views/default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarty Conditionals</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/conditionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/conditionals/</guid>
      <description>Smarty Conditionals Smarty includes a base amount of logic that you can insert into your template. One of these is a conditional statement. A couple of basic examples should give you an idea of the syntax and format of Smarty conditionals.
This example uses the user data from the controller&amp;rsquo;s data array to print out a welcome message if the user is signed in and a generic message if the user is not signed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarty Functions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/</guid>
      <description>Smarty Functions This section outlines all the Vanilla-specific Smarty functions made available for use in your Smarty templates.
You are also able to use the built-in Smarty functions in your template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smarty Modifiers</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/modifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/modifiers/</guid>
      <description>Smarty Modifiers Smarty modifiers can be applied to variables, custom functions or strings. You can use a modifier by adding a | (pipe) after the element you wish to modify and adding the modifier name. Modifiers can also accept parameters which are separated by a : (colon). These parameters must follow the order of their appearance in the signature.
Vanilla supports the built-in Smarty modifiers as documented on the Smarty site, and has created a few more for you to use in your templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Connect Plugins</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/</guid>
      <description>Social Connect Plugins Vanilla Forums integrates with a number of social applications that you can use as SSO solutions. Learn more about configuring these applications to work with your forum in this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/spam/</guid>
      <description>Spam Prevention Vanilla is equipped with several layers of SPAM prevention. While automated tools do most of the work, we encourage you to be vigilant and to enlist your membership to report any suspected spam.
Spam Detection Vanilla includes 2 spam detection plugins: StopForumSpam and Akismet. These can be turned on in your Dashboard from the Addons page. * Akismet: this plugin feeds your posts through the Akismet spam detection algorythm which looks at several factors including live data to determine if a post is spam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staging Site</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/staging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/staging/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Staging Site Overview For higher plan levels, we provide a separate staging forum. You can use this account for testing addons, features, and theme changes before they reach your production site. Your customer success manager will provide this account for you upon request.
Test data We do not typically use your staging forum as the destination for your test migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/support/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Cloud Support We provide professional support exclusively for our cloud clients. Because of this, we require the forum owner to request support, or to specifically authorize other users to receive support.
Support is available by:
 Using the &amp;ldquo;Support&amp;rdquo; form in your Dashboard. Visiting the official support forum at https://support.vanillaforums.com. Sign in with the same email you used to register for cloud hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported platforms</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/support/</guid>
      <description>Supported platforms Migration tools are available for the following platforms. All migration tools minimally support users, categories, discussions, and comments. For a current per-platform, per-feature support list, see the Vanilla Porter.
PHP forums  Vanilla 1 phpBB 2-3 vBulletin 3-5 bbPress 1 SimplePress 1 Simple Machines 1-2 PunBB 1 IP.Board 3 XenForo Joomla Kunena Drupal Advanced Forum MyBB esoTalk Expression Engine  ASP / .NET forums Requires conversion to MySQL first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/tagging/</guid>
      <description>Overview Tagging is a feature that allows users to add keywords to discussions. For public communities, tags help label specific content for improved findability. When used with advanced search, they help isolate content by a relevant topic and improve results. Tagging also has a theme module, which can serve as site navigation.
Enabling Tagging Tagging is not enabled by default for new communities, it will need to be toggled on by and administrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Overview</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/overview/</guid>
      <description>jsConnect For jsConnect to work you&amp;rsquo;ll put some code on your site that identifies your users in a way that Vanilla can understand. Vanilla then requests this information when the user wants to sign in and synchronizes the user with Vanilla. This is done via JSONP, which allows us to send your cookies from your site to you and obtain login information.
Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s web-based single sign on (SSO) has 2 parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Options</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/themeoptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/themeoptions/</guid>
      <description>Theme Options This is a rather advanced theme configuration and is often unnecessary but can be very useful in certain circumstances.
You can configure a custom dashboard settings page for your theme that allows an admin to choose between different CSS files in your theme&amp;rsquo;s design folder. You can also allow an admin to add custom text to your theme.
This functionality can be added simply by editing your theme&amp;rsquo;s about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Visibility</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/themevisibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/themevisibility/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  If you&amp;rsquo;ve got Vanilla Cloud, custom themes will be hidden by default. This is to ensure custom themes are only visible to their respective owners.
In order of importance, here are the rules for a theme to be visible:
Method 1: If the theme is set to be visible with this site option:
Garden.Themes.Visible  You can add multiple sites by separating sites with a comma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theming</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/</guid>
      <description>Theming Overview Vanilla themes are built by selectively overriding the views and CSS in the product. They are also imbued with the power of plugins via a special hooks file.
It is extremely important to never modify Vanilla by directly editing the files distributed in the release. Nearly anything can by accomplished with views, CSS, and hooks in a properly formatted theme.
Quickstart To override CSS, create a custom.css file in your theme; it will be included in the page after our CSS, so you can override without higher specificity or !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting Vanilla These are some generic tips for addressing problems during an upgrade.
 Set $Configuration[&#39;Debug&#39;] = TRUE; in your conf/config.php to reveal full error messages. Remember to remove it when you are done. Clear your browser cache and cookies, then restart your browser. Clear *.ini files from the cache folder. Revert to the default theme. You can do this manually in conf/config.php by setting the $Configuration[&#39;Garden&#39;][&#39;Theme&#39;] value to default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/social/twitter/</guid>
      <description>Twitter Twitter Connect allows users to sign in using their Twitter account. You must register your application with Twitter for this plugin to work.
Setting up social login in Twitter Connect  Register Vanilla with Twitter at: https://apps.twitter.com/app/new Set the Callback URL by appending /entry/twauthorize to the end of your forum’s URL. (If your forum is at example.com/forum, your Callback URL would be http://example.com/forum/entry/twauthorize). After registering, copy the &amp;ldquo;Consumer Key&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Consumer Secret&amp;rdquo; into your Twitter plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal Comments</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/comments/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla Comments Vanilla comments allow any website with a unique content id to add a commenting system that can seamlessly integrate with their Vanilla community. Comments made on content on their website will create discussions in their community. Also any comment made on the forum discussion will be reflected back under the content.
What are Universal Comments? We made Comment integration easy with WordPress (learn more about that here.), but we also wanted to make it possible to add comments to any site where you can identify unique content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading from Warnings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/upgrading-from-warnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/upgrading-from-warnings/</guid>
      <description>Warnings &amp;amp; Notes is version 2 The first version of this addon was titled simply &amp;ldquo;Warnings&amp;rdquo;. It did not include the User Notes feature. It had more granular controls for Warning a user with particular point levels and durations.
We recommend all users disable the &amp;ldquo;Warnings&amp;rdquo; addon if they still have it and immediately enable the &amp;ldquo;Warnings &amp;amp; Notes&amp;rdquo; addon instead.
Why does &amp;ldquo;Warnings &amp;amp; Notes&amp;rdquo; have less granular settings?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use API on External Sites</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/use-api-on-external-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/use-api-on-external-site/</guid>
      <description>The Vanilla Forums API can be used to display information from your community outside of the community such as your blog. This guide shows a basic example using javascript and jQuery.
JSONP Default browser security does not let you make API calls from an external site. This is necessary to prevent a wide range of hacking and in general keeps the web a safer place. However, to get around this limitation with the API Vanilla uses a technology called JSONP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Comments</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/using-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/using-comments/</guid>
      <description>Transition to Vanilla Comments Vanilla doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to your WordPress comments, so simply turning off WP&amp;rsquo;s comments and turning on Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s would hide all your existing comments. There&amp;rsquo;s 3 ways to go about remedying this.
The first is to import all your WordPress comments to Vanilla. You will need need the XML export from your WordPress Dashboard to do this. VanillaForums.com clients may request this as an additional service via support or their sales representative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Ranks as Incentives</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/using-ranks-as-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/using-ranks-as-incentives/</guid>
      <description>Using Ranks: Incentives You can use Ranks as an incentive for members to participate by rewarding them for more and better participation.
Example Case What follows is an example for abilities to grant to higher ranks. It uses the default ranks Levels 1-5 and assumes the default Criteria of 50, 100, 500, and 1000 points for Level 2 thru 5 consecutively.
Gaining points on your site is done thru addons such as Badges and Reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Ranks to Defeat Spam or Abuse</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/using-ranks-to-defeat-spam-or-abuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/using-ranks-to-defeat-spam-or-abuse/</guid>
      <description>Using Ranks: Spam Ranks can be used to limit the ability of spammers to take advantage of your site and protect members from abuse. To do this, limit the abilities of your newest users until they have been proven their value to the community.
Who is this for? This guide is for communities currently having spam problems that have already tried other automated filtering solutions like Akismet and Stop Forum Spam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Config</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/using/</guid>
      <description>When to use the config Use the config for saving settings in your theme or plugin. You should only save small amounts of data to the config, and it should not be data that is changed frequently.
If you have large quantities of data or data that is written frequently, consider using the database instead.
Reading from config The c function is the appropriate shortcut for reading from the config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Web Fonts</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/custom-theme/webfont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/custom-theme/webfont/</guid>
      <description>Using Web Fonts The easiest way to change the font in the base theme is to use a web font. You will have to add a link to the font in the theme HTML and target the
For example, to change the font to the Google Font Lato:
 Get the link snippet from fonts.google.com: &amp;lt;link href=&amp;quot;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Lato&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Get the CSS rule: font-family: &#39;Lato&#39;, sans-serif; Go to HTML tab on the Customize Theme page of the Vanilla Dashboard Add the font link snippet above in between the  tags Add the following to the CSS tab: body {font-family: &#39;Lato&#39;, sans-serif;}  Notes: * Knowledge of CSS is required to use the CSS customization features of Vanilla * If you would like to install a font that is not available as a webfont, please contact Vanilla support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla API</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/api/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla has had a read-only ReSTful API for some time, but until now, no formal way to access any write methods. This all changes with Simple API. Now developers can access Vanilla’s write methods using an access_token configured in the dashboard.
Configuring Simple API Simple API is a plugin. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve enabled the plugin you’ll see a new link in your dashboard called &amp;ldquo;API&amp;rdquo;. This page allows forum owners to set the access token, define a user account that will be used for API access, and determine whether API calls are allowed over HTTP and HTTPS, or just HTTPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla API v2</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/apiv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/apiv2/</guid>
      <description>The Vanilla API v2 is the latest version of Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s RESTful API. We&amp;rsquo;ve taken all the lessons learned from our first API and made a more consistent, useful API for integrating within your applications.
Improvements in API v2  More authentication options including per-user access tokens. A live API reference in your dashboard where you can reference API methods and make calls right from within the documentation. More endpoints so you can control more of your site from the API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Pop</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/vanilla-pop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/vanilla-pop/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Email Interaction Vanilla Pop is a feature of Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s Enterprise forums that allows you to interact with your forum through email.
 With Vanilla Pop you can: Reply to an emailed discussion on the forum or through email. Have conversations through email, but keep a record on Vanilla.  Your Forum&amp;rsquo;s Email Address The top of the page tells you your forum&amp;rsquo;s email address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Pop with Site Hub</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/vanilla-pop/site-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/vanilla-pop/site-hub/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Differences Vanilla Pop works in much the same way on the hub as it does on regular sites. The node email addresses are slightly different and there are a few more features which are detailed below.
Node Email Addresses Each node&amp;rsquo;s email address is comprised of two parts: The node slug and the hub slug seperated by a dot, followed by a vanillaforums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Porter</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/porter/</guid>
      <description>Migrating a forum to Vanilla Vanilla Porter is the export tool for converting your legacy forum to Vanilla. The process is four steps:
 Export your old forum data to a special &amp;ldquo;Porter file&amp;rdquo;. Create a new Vanilla forum. Import the Porter file in Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s Dashboard. Verify &amp;amp; finalize your new forum.  Vanilla Porter requires a MySQL database and PHP 5.3+ with zlib support enabled.
Before migrating We recommend these best practices:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Views</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/views/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/views/</guid>
      <description>Views Once a controller method is called to handle the request, how is the xhtml of the page put together? Views. There are two types of views in Garden: &amp;ldquo;Views&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Master Views&amp;rdquo;. A view relates directly to the controller method that called it and handles rendering content related to that request. You can typically think of a view as the content for that page. For example, if a Vanilla-&amp;gt;Discussion-&amp;gt;All() method is called, the view for that method would handle rendering all of the discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Views / HTML</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/views/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/views/</guid>
      <description>Theming Views The master view The master view for your forum is the wrapper for each page in your forum. Often, this is the only view you&amp;rsquo;ll have to manipulate in your theme. The master view file is called the default.master.tpl (Smarty template) or the default.master.php. We recommend using Smarty templates for your master view, however you can decide to use a regular ol&amp;rsquo; php view if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning a User</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/warning-a-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/warning-a-user/</guid>
      <description>Warning a User You can warn a user from their profile, or from a post that they’ve made. Warnings may be given by users with the permission Garden.Moderation.Manage or Moderation.Warnings.Add (if present).
Profile Warning To warn a user from their profile click on their edit profile drop down. There should be an item called Warn.
Warn from a Post You can warn a user for a post they’ve made. To do this click on the post’s flag menu and click Warn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warnings and Notes</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/</guid>
      <description>What are Warnings? Warnings can be given to users by moderators for behavior that is not appropriate in the community. Warnings use a points system that increases a user’s warning level with successive warnings until the warnings expire. Once users reach certain points thresholds they can be jailed or banned.
What are Notes? User notes are notes attached to individual users that only moderators can add and see. They allow moderators to keep track of information about users that may be important to other moderators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WishList Integration</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/wishlist/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Integration</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/integrations/wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Wordpress Integration Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s integration to Wordpress lets you do a few things:
 SSO from Wordpress to Vanilla Use Vanilla as a commenting system on your Wordpress blog Add a widget to your Wordpress site.  Vanilla plugin for Wordpress You can find the Wordpress plugin here.
Integration Setup Instructions Integration instructions can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing API Endpoints</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/api-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/api-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>Controller Endpoints When writing an API controller class, each method represents an endpoint. How to define those endpoint names and parameters is covered in the resource routing guide. This guide concerns writing the contents of a method.
The Controller Base Class Although controllers don&amp;rsquo;t need to inherit from any class, the Vanilla\Web\Controller class offers useful functionality and is going to be the class you inherit from almost 100% of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing APIs</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/apiv2/</guid>
      <description>The Vanilla APIv2 Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s APIv2 offers a powerful, yet simple way of creating RESTful API endpoints in your application. With version 2 of the API we consider Vanilla to be an &amp;ldquo;API first&amp;rdquo; framework where you write your API first and then think about the resulting HTML. This offers several benefits:
 An API is easier to test, lending well to automated testing. You can connect to an API from different clients and not just browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zendesk</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/zendesk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/zendesk/</guid>
      <description>Overview This plugin allows you to:
 Link your Zendesk account to your Vanilla user profile. Submit users&amp;rsquo; discussions and comments as tickets to your hosted Zendesk.  Setup If you already have an account you need to enable API Access for this plugin to work.
 Login to your Zendesk Site. Go to the Admin Setting. Under Channels Select API. Select the OAuth Clients. Add a client. Complete the form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about.php</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/about-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/about-php/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;about.php&amp;rdquo; file Each theme has an about.php file that contains some important information for Vanilla. Put this file in your theme root.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample file:
&amp;lt;?php $ThemeInfo[&#39;ExampleTheme&#39;] = [ &#39;Name&#39; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Example Theme&amp;quot;, &#39;Description&#39; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Custom theme example&amp;quot;, &#39;Version&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;1.0.0&#39;, &#39;Author&#39; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Stéphane LaFlèche&amp;quot;, &#39;AuthorEmail&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;stephane.l@vanillaforums.com&#39;, &#39;AuthorUrl&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;www.vanillaforums.com&#39;, &#39;License&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;Proprietary&#39;, &#39;Layout&#39; =&amp;gt; [ &#39;Discussions&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;table&#39;, &#39;Categories&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;modern&#39;, ] ];  Theme &amp;ldquo;key&amp;rdquo; $ThemeInfo[&#39;ExampleTheme&#39;]  It&amp;rsquo;s important to put a unique key here for your theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jsConnect</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/sso/jsconnect/</guid>
      <description>Why jsConnect? SSO systems are complex. Setting up your own SAML or OAuth system takes a lot of time, and generally is not feasible for small-to-medium business owners.
If you have a website that stores your user&amp;rsquo;s identity and the only thing you need to integrate is a forum, jsConnect is a far simpler solution. This is because we&amp;rsquo;ve abstracted most of the work to our side of the connection, and provide sample code for making your side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nginx</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/server-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/backend/server-nginx/</guid>
      <description>nginx Configuration The key to specifically running Vanilla under nginx is getting the basic rewrite rule in nginx.conf correct. You can see a working example in the Hardening section.
Some tips: - When configuring fastcgi make sure that you use $realpath_root instead of $document_root. - Make sure that you set the fastcgi_param X_REWRITE parameter to 1.
Hardening Here are some directories that should be forbidden:
location ~* &amp;quot;/\.git&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/build/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/cache/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/cgi-bin/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/uploads/import/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/conf/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/tests/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; } location ~* &amp;quot;^/vendor/&amp;quot; { deny all; return 403; }  We alo recommend to disallow any script but /index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{asset}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/asset/</guid>
      <description>Function: {asset} Usage {asset name=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; tag=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Renders an asset from the controller.
Assets in Vanilla are containers for different sets of content. The content of each of these asset containers is variable depending on the page. The content of each asset is not currently configurable via the template.
Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s asset names are Head, Foot, Content and Panel. Your template will need to contain the Head, Foot and Content assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{breadcrumbs}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/breadcrumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/breadcrumbs/</guid>
      <description> Function: {breadcrumbs} Usage {breadcrumbs homelink=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; hidelast=boolean}  Render a breadcrumb trail for the user based on the page they are on.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    homelink  string  Home  Title of the first link in the breadcrumbs  homeurl  string  /  URL of the first link in the breadcrumbs  hidelast  boolean  false  Whether or not to hide the currently active (last) crumb    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{custom_menu}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/custom-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/custom-menu/</guid>
      <description> Function: {custom_menu} Usage {custom_menu format=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; wrap=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  A bucket for addon menu items. Adds links depending on which addons are enabled.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    format  string  none  Custom format to use when wrapping links. Available template variables are %url, %class, and %text  wrap  string  li  Element to wrap around each link in the menu    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{event}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/event/</guid>
      <description> Function: {event} Usage {event name=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Fire an event with the specified name. Learn more about events in Vanilla.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    name  string  none  Name of the event to fire    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{homepage_title}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/homepage-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/homepage-title/</guid>
      <description>Function: {homepage_title} Usage {homepage_title}  Writes the site title to the page. You can change the site title from the &amp;lsquo;Banner&amp;rsquo; settings page in the dashboard.
Parameters This tag does not take any parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{include_file}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/include-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/include-file/</guid>
      <description> Function: {include_file} Usage {include_file name=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Inserts the contents the specified file into the template. The file must be in the same directory as the Smarty template file. Especially useful for inserting html headers or footers into a Smarty template.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    name  string  none  The name of the file to include    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{link}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/link/</guid>
      <description>Function: {link} Usage {link path=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; text=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; notag=boolean format=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; withdomain=boolean}  Takes a route and prepends the web root (expects /controller/action/params as path).
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    path  string  none  The relative path for the url. There are some special paths that can be used to return &amp;lsquo;intelligent&amp;rsquo; links  text  string  none  HTML text to be put inside an anchor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{logo}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/logo/</guid>
      <description>Function: {logo} Usage {logo}  Writes the site logo to the page. You can change the site logo from the &amp;lsquo;Banner&amp;rsquo; settings page in the dashboard.
Parameters This tag does not take any parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{mobile_logo}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/mobile-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/mobile-logo/</guid>
      <description>Function: {mobile_logo} Usage {mobile_logo}  Writes the mobile logo to the page. You can change the mobile logo from the &amp;lsquo;Banner&amp;rsquo; settings page in the dashboard.
Parameters This tag does not take any parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{module}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/module/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/module/</guid>
      <description>Function: {module} Usage {module name=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; ... }  This is a super handy little function that renders any module in Vanilla. It instantiates the specified module class, sets the properties specified in the function&amp;rsquo;s parameters and calls the toString() function of the module.
The available parameters differ depending on module itself and the available modules depend on which addons are enabled. If a module is contained in an addon, the addon must be enabled in order for the module to render (a common gotcha).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{permission}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/permission/</guid>
      <description> Block: {permission} Usage {permission require=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;} Foo {/permission}  Only output content if the current user has the specified permission.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    require  string  none  The permission to check / require    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{pocket}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/pocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/pocket/</guid>
      <description> Function: {pocket} Usage {pocket name=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Writes a pocket to the page. Pockets placed in the template in this way should have their location set to &amp;lsquo;custom&amp;rsquo;. You can edit this setting from the &amp;lsquo;Pockets&amp;rsquo; settings page in the dashboard.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    name  string  none  The name of the pocket    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{searchbox}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/searchbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/searchbox/</guid>
      <description> Function: {searchbox} Usage {searchbox placeholder=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Writes the search box to the page.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    placeholder  string  Search  Optional input box placeholder text    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{text}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/text/</guid>
      <description> Function: {text} Usage {text code=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; default=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Returns the custom text from a theme&amp;rsquo;s options page. Learn more about how to configure your theme options.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    code  string  none  The text code set in the theme&amp;rsquo;s information array  default  string  none  The default text if the user hasn&amp;rsquo;t overridden    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>{t}</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/i18n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/theming/smarty/functions/i18n/</guid>
      <description> Function: {t} Usage {t c=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; d=&amp;quot;string&amp;quot;}  Output a translatable string with an optional default.
Parameters   Parameter Type Default Description    c  string  none  The string to output or a string short-name  d  string  $c  Default translation. Good idea to set when using short-names    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>