<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Help-rsses on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Help-rsses on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, VIP releases were every other month. Other customers received updates on an ad-hoc basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;december&#34;&gt;December&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add full IPv6 support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add and improve addon icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add meta tags for discussion links to generate Twitter cards (when added to tweets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add settings to Dashboard for category max display depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some padding to HTML tables in posts (improve legibility).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for our new CDN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add accessibility attributes to Customize Theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pager to log views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve category headings detection and table view support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve markup of category settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure password editing fields toggle appropriately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow removal of button from HTML email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore Theme Preview functionality (except for Mobile 2014).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default to secure cookies if &amp;ldquo;ForceSSL&amp;rdquo; is set and using HTTPS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip validating discussion title when a draft is saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve markup and make further enhancements to Dashboard v3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict upload filename to be per post instead of by entire discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow uploading a Photo when creating a new category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid auto-scrolling to top when in comment embed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm that user wants to delete images before deleting (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update documentation links for Social Connect addons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace &amp;ldquo;Hide Category&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Mute Category&amp;rdquo; option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow new messages to accept a subject parameter (if enabled) via URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix delete message button (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix delete ban button (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix category depth calculation in subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix IP filtering on user management page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix heading categories sometimes being wrapped in an anchor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix dashboard pager next button when there are 0 results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the user photo in search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix extra &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags in plain text emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where nav is cut off on category add/edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix wrong heading for &amp;ldquo;activity&amp;rdquo; on profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix activity notifications falsely flagging as sent when it was skipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix ICO transparency issue after upload (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix permission check for Change Log page to allow moderators (Moderation.Manage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix avatar cropping in profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jsConnect: Add warning to jsConnect dashboard when provider is in test mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jsConnect: [Security] Add content-type to callback endpoint to prevent potential XSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badges: Add badge name as alt text to badge images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badges: Add the ability to edit thresholds for some badges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix results percentage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix cancel button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Hide category dropdown when already inside a category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix auto-selecting first child category in category dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A: Fix auto-selecting first child category in category dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Add inform message to Reactions enable toggle (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix RSS view when BestOf is configured as tiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix customizations reverting after database updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: [Security] Add missing CSRF protection on &amp;ldquo;react&amp;rdquo; endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix reactions popup possible overlap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Translate reaction names in navigation breadcrumbs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MailChimp: Fix issue with synchronizing lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile Extender: Fix checkbox display on registration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore: Fix failure to unignore user if their ignore privileges have been revoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Fix search in groups when the category is not viewable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warnings &amp;amp; Notes: Fix extra line after quote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civil Tongue: Add support for groups and group events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salesforce: Remove from options on profile social connect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split/Merge: Make the System user the new discussion&amp;rsquo;s author when splitting comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAML: Allow SAML to accommodate differently-configured XML responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SimpleAPI: Fix situations where other addons could conflict with API endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;september&#34;&gt;September&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Dashboard! This changed every page in the moderator/admin backend, including all addon settings pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add navigation memory to the Dashboard. It will now preserve menu collapsing states &amp;amp; your page within each section between visits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &amp;ldquo;Flat Categories&amp;rdquo; feature and optional navigation module. This allows browsing hundreds of categories as an alphabetical directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve how categories are managed in the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories now default to type &amp;ldquo;Nested&amp;rdquo; and must have a type assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add full recipients list to Badges. Click the &amp;ldquo;Given&amp;rdquo; number from &amp;ldquo;Badges&amp;rdquo; in the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new &amp;ldquo;Post Numbering&amp;rdquo; addon (by request only, currently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new &amp;ldquo;Role Tracker&amp;rdquo; addon (by request only, currently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to convert discussions to &amp;ldquo;ideas&amp;rdquo; (if Ideation is enabled).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to configure warnings in Warnings &amp;amp; Notes addon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add redirects for Lithium and Ning community imports (Redirector addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for vBulletin 3 &amp;amp; 4 showthread.php?p={POSTID} URL redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow &amp;ldquo;Location&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; to be edited from User Edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Profile Extender&amp;rsquo;s handling of non-ASCII characters in field names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored how we handle all requests (dispatcher).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update MailChimp addon to use v3 of their API and support MailChimp &amp;ldquo;groups&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Facebook addon to use versioned endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix &amp;ldquo;Mark All Viewed&amp;rdquo; endpoint to prevent accidental or malicious triggering and fix its redirect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Bootstrap3 theme color schemes &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sandstone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;SafeStyles&amp;rdquo; option (previously deprecated).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General addon code maintenance done on: Groups, Reactions, Ranks, Polls, SAMLSSO, and Badges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue with embedding where you could stay scrolled down when changing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add username validation to /message/add endpoint (when pre-filling &amp;ldquo;To:&amp;rdquo; field via URL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix conflict between Discussion Photos addon and Ideation addon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability for Smarty templates to access &lt;code&gt;isMobile&lt;/code&gt; function, &lt;code&gt;userAgentType&lt;/code&gt; function, &lt;code&gt;homepage_title&lt;/code&gt; function, and &lt;code&gt;Homepage&lt;/code&gt; (boolean variable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where default role settings weren&amp;rsquo;t transferred from old system correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add additional line break to welcome email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not wrap images in a div if they are already in an anchor to fix potential clicking issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix autocomplete dropdown display in modals with Bootstrap3 theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the post that a user was warned for in the email notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not serve empty (or comment-only) CSS files from Custom Theme feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix photos&amp;rsquo; URL for /user/summary API endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix quotes that are done on a user with spaces in its name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;tabindex&lt;/code&gt; for comments, conversations, discussions (for keyboard navigation around page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add announcements to discussions RSS (in posting order).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block adding banning rules that would HAL-9000 the entire crew, like &lt;code&gt;*.*&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the basic (not advanced, which had no issue) search pager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not revalidate username on edit if no change on user edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not send &lt;code&gt;noindex&lt;/code&gt; meta on error pages to prevent legit pages from being un-indexed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the priority of custom.css to be higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix log link showing when no log exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow &amp;ldquo;Unanswered Questions&amp;rdquo; page title to be translated (Q&amp;amp;A addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for alternate SAML document structures (SSO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enforce max tags limit on the front end and cleanup tag validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode slashes in usernames when creating profile links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow comment drafts to be orphaned (instead of removed) when their discussion is deleted and rework drafts view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unregister plugins immediately after it has been disabled instead of waiting until the next page request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide email preferences when email is disabled globally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide the RSS icon from categories that are type &amp;lsquo;Categories&amp;rsquo; since they contain no discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trim all control characters from discussion title (helps prevent broken or blank titles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix scenario where discussion title could be blank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix user search to allow numeric usernames as long as it&amp;rsquo;s an exact match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Akismet will now validate your key before accepting it (Cloud customers do not require their own key; it is optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Akismet addon description and deprecate TypePad option (no longer offered by TypePad).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide Participated menu for guests (Participated addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let welcome email fallback to HomepageTitle when the site&amp;rsquo;s name is not set properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off autocomplete on text fields when editing users in dashboard (to prevent accidental data insertion).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve how table layouts choose their column widths according to the content in them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Q&amp;amp;A and how it interacts with Subcommunities, especially displaying an Unanswered count per community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change H2s for H1s for a few edit profile pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve consistency in module (widget) titles (usually H4) so they are properly configurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add invited user data to user exports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix button height in Share This widget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add OAuth2 library to core product for building custom implementations more easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix potential duplicate rank promotion notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the priority order of the SimpleAPI plugin so Subcommunities does not interfere with API calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;july&#34;&gt;July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New plugin: Role Tracker (aggregates discussions with posts by users in particular roles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New plugin: Welcome Post (invites newly registered to start an intro discussion immediately).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade to Smarty 3 templating engine for custom themes. It&amp;rsquo;s a little bit stricter, faster, and more secure than Smarty 2 was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further improve scaling for large numbers of categories. Faster page loads!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to exclude moderators and/or admins from leaderboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move profile thumbnail editing to same page as photo uploading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenID: Prevent bad rendering when URL is invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t show Google+ login when enabled but not configured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for inline (async) forms for future Vanilla use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep attachments when a discussion becomes a comment via Split/Merge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically update CSRF token with async requests. This is so we can invalidate them more frequently in the future, improving our security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ideation page as a target for messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the categories page as a target for messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a limit on the page number in Best Of (it helps performance to not let pages go infinitely high).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix edge cases where notifications preferences would not display completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tighten security of Target parameter during sign in to disallow bad redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refresh the page after announcing a discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown: Allow starting lists without a newline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change how IP addresses are logged and allow IPv6 (no more 0.0.0.2 placeholder addresses appearing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the invite feature from the Getting Started page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove site logo from Deflector theme footer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Cyrillic character recognition in CivilTongueEx, allowing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Ideation crashing /discussions/promoted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix default translation of &amp;ldquo;Post Discussion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Fix &amp;ldquo;unanswered&amp;rdquo; status for discussions converted to questions by an admin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Add synchronize for subcommunities and default locale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix emoji menu not being properly dismissed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide &amp;ldquo;Dismiss&amp;rdquo; option on announcements from guests because it didn’t actually do anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add CSRF prevention and remove redirect from Mark All Viewed option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode mail subject properly (UTF-8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix broken reaction pagination on profile pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix emoji and mention from rendering inside WYSIWYG code blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add $Homepage Smarty variable that is true/false depending on if you are on the homepage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix double encoding Open Graph title tag. This would have shown up as extra ampersands in Facebook shares and the like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Do not sync category permissions for an overridden role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Add optional landing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to separate library for password hashing. We&amp;rsquo;re compartmentalizing some features like this to make maintenance easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We completed some very large projects to carefully rework several parts of our framework to get ready for API v2, but there&amp;rsquo;s no outward effect of this for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;may&#34;&gt;May&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade to reCaptcha 2 (&amp;ldquo;NoCaptcha&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &amp;ldquo;NBBC&amp;rdquo; our new BBCode parsing library by default (no more plugin).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability for SAML SSO to not be the default login method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow moving a discussion between subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for switching subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve category scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make activities self-prune after 2 months to improve performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always redirect to the first page after saving a discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add analytics tracking for Q&amp;amp;A&amp;rsquo;s accepted answers (coming soon to analytics).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow censoring content in conversation message notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow censoring poll votes in comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a number of edge cases where certain actions could block other actions without a page refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix condition where category announcements disappeared from recent discussions page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add caching for the default authentication provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve security in signin redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve use of &amp;lsquo;Alt&amp;rsquo; CSS class, which will be removed eventually (now redundant with current CSS specs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to configure a redirect after logout on Auth0 plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Triple-A and Bootstrap 3 themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where Vimeo and Instagram embeds overflow out of the Best Of Tiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix where SplitMerge addon may be unable to save split discussion with &amp;ldquo;Html&amp;rdquo; format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the love bug (various problems with &amp;lt; 3 in user-generated content).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent unneeded recurring updates in dashboard&amp;rsquo;s database updater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Gravatar&amp;rsquo;s use of system default avatar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add optional rating parameter to Gravatar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix GitHub signin and API permission issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix new discussion button showing in subcommunity when user has no permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the Photo field to be set in /profile/edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only use CommentID for spam check if available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix incorrect permission being checked in some category management actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Simplify &amp;amp; fix event timezone handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make initial spoiler text the same colour as its background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix RSS title encoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to capture a user&amp;rsquo;s time zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix LinkedIn &amp;ldquo;profile connect&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move Recaptcha into a plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for Instagram embeds in Mobile 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do more image optimizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Safari issue where back button wouldn&amp;rsquo;t refresh the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where people can quote a post and see uncensored content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove gender from user-facing elements like registration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent &amp;ldquo;Messages&amp;rdquo; from being displayed when you do not have view permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Return the correct number of questions for a subcommunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch YouTube links to https.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix mention issues including using an &amp;lsquo;@&amp;rsquo; in the middle of two words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix PNG compression issues in file uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix some minor issues that could make spoilers malfunction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a safety feature to avoid too-big database changes all at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow any user with moderate permission to add discussions and events in a group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix aggressive span stripping in the HTML purifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;march&#34;&gt;March&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Ideation (vote on ideas) - Contact your CSM for more details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Microsoft Account SSO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: CAS SSO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Keyword Blocker (send posts with certain keywords to mod queue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Necro Posts (labels recently-revived discussions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: User Points Booster (allow awarding points for discussions or comments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Whitelist (provide an IP whitelist for site access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML emails now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicants list is now asynchronous with improved UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoilers added as core feature with updated formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic bans (from Banning rules) can now be reversed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions will now always show on all devices, instead of on-hover for larger screens (&amp;ldquo;desktop&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign In form now auto-focuses on Username field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix newest comment data for zero-comment discussions in table view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post excerpts (as in search) now have a minimum length of 32 even if a double-return is found first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove line breaks in meta description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added events to support new analytics system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix styling of &amp;lsquo;/me&amp;rsquo; posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Allow users to accept their own answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Add an option to allow users to react to their own posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add advanced editor options to New Poll screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix plus signs in URLs, especially usernames / profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve SSO workflow for existing usernames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework discussion sorting and filtering architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add no-store header to profiles so read/unread status updates on Back button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pockets: fix repeating pockets between discussions, and enable on table view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subcommunities: Fix category dropdown filtering when in a subcommunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide editor toolbar when previewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix double-deletion of comment drafts when posting, which could cause a Javascript error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix scenario where Quotes could interfere with Spoilers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanillicons: Now defaults to v2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NBBC: Fix scenario that could break search results formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix opaque photo cropping box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix and unify logic for determining permission to edit a user&amp;rsquo;s photo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow quotes to be collapsed in reported posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow collapsing of quotes with alternate formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make even deeply-nested quotes minimally legible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update dropdown menu rendering in several places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update number formatting for discussion &amp;amp; comment counts on All Categories page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update stock themes for Ideation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Allow anyone who can edit an event to also delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;january&#34;&gt;January&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore no-store header to discussion &amp;amp; category lists (fixes &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; markers not updating on &amp;ldquo;Back&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved formatting of Vanilla Comments in certain input formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Smarty template parsing library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix an issue in draft saving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix spam deletion error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Editor to use files&amp;rsquo; real names when downloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix RSS feed when table view is in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove deprecated form field name prefixing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more category data to VanillaPop emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update gifv embed to prefer WebM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various low-level fixes for PHP 7 compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix CSRF check when deleting a ban.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close open redirect &amp;amp; fix flood control in database updating endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve security in how Vimeo is embedded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Wistia embed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enforce POST data for several endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve theme compatibility with Groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically remove spaces around Banning rules to prevent bad data being entered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve image resizing to always use highest quality images possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Facebook SSO: retrieval of email address, avatar distortion, &amp;amp; name overwriting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;dashboard&amp;rdquo; namespace from several dashboard URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix several MySQL strict mode errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove livequery jQuery extension and all remaining uses of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove base64 encoding from all asynchronous requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow setting of avatar via API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow category permissions to be set via API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow certain configurations to be set depending on permission level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-add user count to the user list whenever possible based on size of table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give full formatting bar to Activity form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarterly VIP releases contain all numbered releases within said quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;q1-release-3-thursday-feb-16&#34;&gt;Q1 release 3 (Thursday, Feb 16)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;q1-release-2-tuesday-jan-31&#34;&gt;Q1 release 2 (Tuesday, Jan 31)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civil Tongue: Censor discussion titles in Recent Discussions list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversations: Tighten maximum recipients allowed: 5 for new users, 50 for verified users, and unlimited for moderators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard: Add settings and improve help text on the &amp;ldquo;Avatars&amp;rdquo; dashboard settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avatar Pool: Settings are now on the &amp;ldquo;Avatars&amp;rdquo; page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online: Fix issue where Online module could cache and display in the wrong language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor: Close editor dropdowns when the user clicks outside of a dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor: Add spoiler and code styles to WYSIWYG preview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor: Mentions auto-complete now quotes all usernames that need it automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor: Fix Markdown list parsing that caused a minor styling glitch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A: Fix point-awarding interactions with Reactions. Accepting and declining answers could previously have unexpected results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API: Allow JSON access to profile when Profile.ShowActivity is disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories: Add a &lt;code&gt;CanDelete&lt;/code&gt; flag to categories (prevents Social Group category deletion which breaks Groups).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories: Fix issue where subcategories could be orphaned when their parent was deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories: Make the category deletion process clearer about what content will be removed and how.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login: Improve password requirements message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs: Add week day, time, and timezone to the moderation logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs: Do not spam-check owner account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addons: Add &amp;ldquo;Configured&amp;rdquo; messages to addons media view to denote whether an addon was been fully configured on their settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addons: Added icons for 3 addons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addons: Fix issue where an addon incorrectly registering permissions could break other permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile: Fix too-large images in mobile theme settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics: Hide the category dropdown where not relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAML: Allow admins to create a data map for SAML responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subcommunities: Fix canonical URLs on discussion and category pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintenance: Improve maintenance mode so it can be automatically used during future database updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintenance: Moved media handling and tagging from addons into core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintenance: Moved several library dependencies out of core (deleted 35,000 lines of code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;q1-release-1-tuesday-jan-17&#34;&gt;Q1 release 1 (Tuesday, Jan 17)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories: Better sync modern category view to be the same as the table view. This insures &amp;ldquo;Display As&amp;rdquo; settings are used consistently between different layout options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banning: Prevent user&amp;rsquo;s visit information from being updated if banned. This is an enhancement to banned behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging: Add logged events for failed logins, password requests, and password reset failures. This is for advanced logging only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quotes: Fix the Quote button not appearing in some cases. This was a user-facing bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Themes: Give themes ability to set their layout options in their &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; info. This is for theme developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drafts: Fix &amp;ldquo;Incorrect integer value&amp;rdquo; error on draft save when no category selected. This was a regression bug in drafts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search: Fix search not returning results from categories with &amp;ldquo;Hide from recent discussions&amp;rdquo; selected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JWT SSO: Improve support and fix minor issues in some connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix inaccuracies in voting UI when user exceeds 1000 votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook: Add support for Facebook&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo; token during SSO. This is a security enhancement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Add groups and events support to Keyword Blocker. The plugin can now send these items to the Moderation Queue for approval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badges: Fix issue where recently manually created badges could not be requested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideation: Make notifications clearer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dozens of low-level bug fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessibility</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/accessibility/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strive for maximum accessibility in our product design and take defects in it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;508 Compliance&amp;rsquo; refers to a US law that requires that US government websites to be accessible to persons with disabilities (e.g. visual or physical impairment).   Accessibility means, among many other things, that a person must be able to use the website with software that reads the website aloud and/or using only a keyboard. Many private companies use the 508 guidelines to ensure websites are accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe Vanilla Forums to be both Section 508 and WCAG AAA compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-points&#34;&gt;Key points&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our default UI is primarily text-based and high-contrast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our interface is keyboard-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We limit the use of colors, images, and symbols as navigation aids or primary content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use modern HTML5 markup and accessible forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We cannot control the accessibility of user generated content within a forum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find an area where Vanilla could improve its accessibility, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;contact support&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/vanilla/vanilla/issues&#34;&gt;file an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;theming-consideration&#34;&gt;Theming consideration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Most Vanilla Forums customize their theme, which can have a huge impact on accessibility.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choices of color and font size are obvious considerations, but because our powerful theming engine also allows for the override of HTML markup, it&amp;rsquo;s important to consider that individual sites may vary wildly in their degree of accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, themes can also augment the interface to improve Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s core accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.508checker.com/best-practices&#34;&gt;Best Practices for 508 Compliance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/topic/accessibility&#34;&gt;A List Apart reading list on Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20&#34;&gt;WCAG 2.0 Recommendation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Badges</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/adding-and-editing-badges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/adding-and-editing-badges/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside class=&#34;cloudfeature&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;Learn More...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disabling-badges&#34;&gt;Disabling badges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To disable a badge and prevent it from displaying publicly, click &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; in the badge&amp;rsquo;s row under the &amp;ldquo;Active&amp;rdquo; column. That will toggle it to &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;, indicating it is no longer active.  Inactive badges remain awarded to any users that received it previously. You can re-enable them by clicking &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;, which will then toggle back to &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;, indicating it is active again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not currently possible to delete a badge entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editing-a-badge&#34;&gt;Editing a badge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can safely edit the Name, Description, and/or Image of any badge without effecting its automated functionality. These will be updated for any users who previously received the badge as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Slug&amp;rdquo; field is what shows in the URL for the badge&amp;rsquo;s page. It is its unique identifier. Changing a badge&amp;rsquo;s Slug will cause it to be disassociated with any automation assigned to it. Therefore, &lt;em&gt;do not change the Slug of the Badges that come with Vanilla by default&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may change the Points for a badge at any time. Point changes are not retroactive for users who previously received it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-your-own-badges&#34;&gt;Creating your own badges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a memorable Name for your badge and give it a Description that explains what it is for and how users can earn it. This information will appear on the Badge&amp;rsquo;s page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slug should consist of only lowercase letters, numbers, and hyphens. The Slug must be unique for each badge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a 200x200 PNG for the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All badges created in your Dashboard must be given manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-automated-badges&#34;&gt;Creating automated badges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not currently possible to create your own automated badges thru the Dashboard. To discuss custom possibilities for your community, contact sales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Ranks</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/adding-and-editing-ranks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/adding-and-editing-ranks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-ranks&#34;&gt;Adding a Ranks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &amp;ldquo;Ranks&amp;rdquo; page of the Dashboard and click the &amp;ldquo;Add Rank&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom of the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editing-a-rank&#34;&gt;Editing a Rank&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &amp;ldquo;Ranks&amp;rdquo; page, click the &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;rdquo; button next to the Rank you wish to modify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rank-information&#34;&gt;Rank information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;name-label&#34;&gt;Name &amp;amp; Label&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name of the rank is how it is referred to. Users will see it in the notification they receive when they attain the rank. The label is what will appear next to the user&amp;rsquo;s name in discussions and comments after they attain the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;body-message&#34;&gt;Body &amp;amp; Message&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These only appear immediately after a user attains a rank. The &amp;ldquo;Body&amp;rdquo; is emailed to the user. The &amp;ldquo;Message&amp;rdquo; appears at the top of the page when the rank is triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;css-class&#34;&gt;CSS Class&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CSS Class is a feature for theme developers. You can assign a valid CSS class to a rank and it will be applied to the wrapper around their discussion or comment. This is useful for making certain ranked users&amp;rsquo; content appear more prominently. For example, if you had an &amp;ldquo;Expert&amp;rdquo; rank, maybe you&amp;rsquo;d highlight their comments with a special background color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;level&#34;&gt;Level&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Level is a number that determines the precedence of assigning ranks. Ranks that are not manual will always attempt to give the user the rank with the highest level that they have met the criteria for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you create a manually assigned rank and do not want any automated ranks to overrule it, make sure it has a higher level than all your automated rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-criteria&#34;&gt;Setting Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set thresholds for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts (comments + discussions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration of membership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permission level (e.g. moderator or admin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All thresholds you set must be met for the rank to be assigned. For instance, if you set Points to 50 and posts to 10, it means a member must have 50 points AND 10 posts to be assigned the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checking &amp;ldquo;Assigned Manually&amp;rdquo; means the criteria is ignored and the rank will only be assigned by a moderator or administrator editing the user&amp;rsquo;s profile and selecting the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;manually-assigning-a-rank&#34;&gt;Manually Assigning a Rank&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rank assignment is done via &amp;ldquo;Edit Profile&amp;rdquo; from the user&amp;rsquo;s profile. Any users in a role with the permission to edit users will be able to assign a rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abilities&#34;&gt;Abilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each ability may be given the value of &amp;ldquo;Grant&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Revoke&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Default&amp;rdquo;. The default value represents what the user would be allowed to do if Ranks was disabled. The grant and revoke options override their normal abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some abilities are effected by other addons. It&amp;rsquo;s important to understand your current Vanilla installation before changing the default values for abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, in a default Vanilla installation, users will not have a &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; field. Therefore, Ranks&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; would be that no one has a Title. However, Profile Extender can be used to add a &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; field, which would give Titles to all users. In that case, Ranks&amp;rsquo; default would be that everyone has a title.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing Reactions</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/adding-and-editing-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/reactions/adding-and-editing-reactions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside class=&#34;cloudfeature&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;Learn More...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selecting-reactions&#34;&gt;Selecting Reactions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla comes with a wide range of reactions in your Dashboard, of which a few are enabled by default. You can toggle them on or off depending on what reactions are appropriate to your community. To enable or disable a reaction on your forum, click the &amp;ldquo;Active/Inactive&amp;rdquo; toggle next to each reaction in the Dashboard under &amp;ldquo;Reactions&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, we recommend using one to four reactions. Reacting should be simple and reflexive, not a complex decision over which reaction to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/addons/reactions/list.png&#34; alt=&#34;The list of Reactions in the Dashboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactions are universal to all categories on your site. You can use CSS rules to hide certain reactions in certain categories, but they cannot be officially disabled selectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-a-reaction&#34;&gt;Edit a Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To edit a reaction, go to Reactions in the Dashboard and click the name of the Reaction you wish to edit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editing an existing reaction is the best way to tweak your list to fit the culture of your community. We recommend selecting the default reaction that most closely matches your desired reaction and simply changing its name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also change the &amp;ldquo;Points&amp;rdquo; field to modify how many points it give to the user receiving each reaction of that type. The number of points assigned to the discussion or comment is not currently editable via the Dashboard. Yes, Reactions assigns points to users and content independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this allows you to keep any automated badges associated with that reaction, which you can then rename appropriately as well. See the Badges - Adding and Editing Badges to see how to do this safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-reaction&#34;&gt;Adding a Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a new reaction, contact support or your sales representative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-settings&#34;&gt;Advanced Settings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access &amp;ldquo;Advanced Settings&amp;rdquo; for Reactions via a link near the top of the Reactions page of the Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/addons/reactions/advanced.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Advanced Settings page&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Show Who Reacted to Posts&amp;rdquo; changes how reaction tallies are displayed under comments. The default is &amp;ldquo;in a popup&amp;rdquo; which requires hovering your mouse pointer over the reaction to see who reacted that way. Use &amp;ldquo;As avatars&amp;rdquo; on small to medium-sized sites to show a row of avatars under each comment for who reacted. Or select &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t show&amp;rdquo; to hide it entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Best of Style&amp;rdquo; changes the layout of your Best Of page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reactions come with the option to order your comments based on reactions. In general, we do not recommend doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Editing User Notes</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/adding-and-editing-user-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/moderation/warnings-and-notes/adding-and-editing-user-notes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adding-a-note&#34;&gt;Adding a Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a note for a user go to their profile. In their edit profile drop down there should be an item called Add Note. Users must have the permission Garden.Moderation.Manage or Moderation.UserNotes.Add (if present) to add notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-notes&#34;&gt;Viewing Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view a user’s notes go to their profile. There will be a notes link on the side panel. Note that both notes and warnings are displayed in the same list. Notes are identified by a note tag. Users must have the permission Garden.Moderation.Manage or Moderation.UserNotes.View (if present) to view notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editing-and-deleting-a-note&#34;&gt;Editing and Deleting a Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can edit and delete user notes by hovering over them and clicking the corresponding button. Users must have the permission Garden.Moderation.Manage or Moderation.UserNotes.Add (if present) to edit or delete notes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addons</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-addons&#34;&gt;What Are Addons?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addons are like apps for your forum. They can be enabled or disabled from your Dashboard. Each one can add one or more features, or modify how an existing feature works. You can tailor your users&amp;rsquo; experience to the needs of your community by carefully selecting addons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla is structured such that its baseline installation only contains features that we feel are essential to every community. Addons let you flavor Vanilla to the specific needs of the community you are building. You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at the rich levels of functionality you can add via addons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enabling-addons&#34;&gt;Enabling Addons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enabling an addon immediately makes it active and available. To do this, visit the addons list and click &amp;ldquo;Enable&amp;rdquo; next to the addon. There may be a delay while enabling a new addon for the first time while it makes whatever changes are needed to your database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuring-addons&#34;&gt;Configuring Addons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After enabling, some addons will have a &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; button that appear next to them in the Addons list. Always visit the Settings page for an addon after enabling it, if it has one, to see if additional setup is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can return to the addon&amp;rsquo;s settings at any time to adjust it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disabling-addons&#34;&gt;Disabling Addons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disabling an addon will remove whatever features it added, but it never destroys the data associated with it. For instance, turning off the Polls addon does not delete any Polls that were created, it just hides them until the addon is enabled again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-addon-features&#34;&gt;Discovering Addon Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addons can do many things. Some common changes include adding new options to the Dashboard&amp;rsquo;s menu, adding information to discussions or comments, changing how parts of the forum work or appear, adding information to user accounts or profiles, or adding new pages of content to your forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every addon comes with a short description of what it does. As a general rule, enabling an addon is fully reversible, so it&amp;rsquo;s safe to turn on any addon and try it out to get a better understanding of how it effects your community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Analytics</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/advanced-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/analytics/advanced-analytics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-analytics&#34;&gt;Advanced Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available as on certain plans or as an add-on, Advanced Aanalytics give you further insights into your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;! &lt;a href=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/analytics/analytics-advanced.png&#34;&gt;Customize Theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;traffic&#34;&gt;Traffic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic statistics can be filtered by date and by category and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Users:&lt;/strong&gt; A count on unique users that logged in to the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Visits by Role Type:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of total visits for each user role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page Views:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of total page views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Users:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of all new registrants to the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;posting&#34;&gt;Posting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posting statistics can be filtered by date and by category and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Discussions:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of all new discussions created.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Comments:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of all new comments created.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Posts:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of all posts (discussion post + comments) created.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Posts by type:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of discussions and of posts created.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Posts by Category:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of posts (discussions + comments) for each category.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Contributors:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of unique contributors (created a discussion or made a comment).
 *&lt;strong&gt;Contributors by Category:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of unique contributors in each category.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Contributors by Role Type:&lt;/strong&gt; A count of unique contributors by role type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;q-a&#34;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q &amp;amp; A statistics can be filtered by time period and category. When multiple lines are displayed, the series are stacked, i.e. the values on the Y axis are a cumulative total for each point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Questions Asked:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of questions created within the time period.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Questions Answered:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of questions answered within the time period, including answers to questions that were created outside the time period selected.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Answers Accepted:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of answers accepted by either the user who created the question or by a moderator/admin. This includes acceptance of questions created outside of the time period selected.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Average Time to Ansnwer:&lt;/strong&gt; The average time taken for a question that was answered within the time period to have been answered.  Questions that were not answered are not included.
 *&lt;strong&gt;Average Time to Accept:&lt;/strong&gt; The average time taken for a question that was accepted to have been accepted. Questions that were not answered or not accepted are not included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;engagement&#34;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement statistics can be filtered by date and by category and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Visits per Active Users:&lt;/strong&gt; The total number of visits divided by the number of active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;average-posts-per-active-users-the-total-number-of-posts-divided-by-the-number-of-active-users&#34;&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Average Posts per Active Users:&lt;/strong&gt; The total number of posts divided by the number of active users.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight: 101
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;aliases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features-analytics-advanced-analytics&#34;&gt;- /features/analytics/advanced-analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-analytics-1&#34;&gt;Advanced Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available on certain plans or as a paid add-on, Advanced Analytics give you further insights into your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/analytics/analytics-advanced.png&#34; alt=&#34;Customize Theme&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;visualization-of-analytics&#34;&gt;Visualization of Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analytics data are presented using three different formats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metrics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Metrics a single number that quantify something for the selected time range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaderboards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leaderboards are tables showing the ranking of specific items for the selected time range. The &amp;ldquo;previous&amp;rdquo; rankings are calculated using the rankings of the previous time range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Graphs can come in multiple forms! They always use information fetched using the selected time range. Line, Area, and Bar graphs use the selected interval to group the fetched information. Pie charts represent multiple values for the whole selected time range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;traffic-1&#34;&gt;Traffic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic analytics can be filtered by date and by category and in some cases by Role.  The analytics presented include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;metrics&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of pages viewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Active users include all registered members and Do Not include unregistered vistors (guests)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Visits include all user types and DO include non registered visitors (guests). Unique visits within the time period are counted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leaderboards&#34;&gt;Leaderboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions with Most Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussions ordered by the highest number of accumulated views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphs&#34;&gt;Graphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Active users include all registered members and Do Not include unregistered vistors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Visits include all user types and DO include non registered visitors (guests). Unique visits within the time period are counted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Visits by Role Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of vianalyticssits, from users, grouped by vanilla&amp;rsquo;s predefined role types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of pages viewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of new users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;posting-1&#34;&gt;Posting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posting analytics can be filtered by date and by category and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;metrics-1&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of discussions created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of comments created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of distinct members who created a post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leaderboards-1&#34;&gt;Leaderboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users with Most Posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Members ordered by the highest number of post created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users with Most Discussions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Members ordered by the highest number of discussions created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphs-1&#34;&gt;Graphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of discussions created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of comments created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of posts created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posts by Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of created posts grouped by posts type (Dicsussions and Comment are the 2 post types).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posts by Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of created posts grouped by categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posts by Role Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of created posts grouped by vanilla&amp;rsquo;s predefined role types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of distinct members having created a post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributors by Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of distinct members, having created a post, grouped by categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributors by Role Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of distinct members, having created a post, grouped by vanilla&amp;rsquo;s predefined role types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;q-a-1&#34;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q &amp;amp; A analytics can be filtered by time period and category. &lt;strong&gt;NB:&lt;/strong&gt; When multiple lines are displayed, the series are stacked, i.e. the values on the Y axis are a cumulative total for each point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;metrics-2&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions Asked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions Answered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of questions having at least one answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answers Accepted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of answers accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Time to Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Average amount of time it took for questions to have their first answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Time to Accept&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Average amount of time it took for questions to have an accepted answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leaderboards-2&#34;&gt;Leaderboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions with Most Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Questions ordered by the highest number of accumulated views.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users with Most Answers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Members ordered by the highest number of answers created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users with Most Accepted Answers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Members ordered by the highest number of answers created and then accepted as the best answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphs-2&#34;&gt;Graphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions Asked&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of questions created.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions Answered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of questions having at least one answer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accepted Answers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of answers accepted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;engagement-1&#34;&gt;Engagement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engagement analytics can be filtered by date and by category and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;metrics-3&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posts Positivity Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of posts having a positive reaction divided by the number of posts having a negative reaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Time to First Comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Average amount of time it took for discussions to have their first comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leaderboards-3&#34;&gt;Leaderboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Members by Accumulated Reputation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Members ordered by the highest sum of reputation point accumulated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions with Most Comments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussions ordered by highest number of comments made in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions with Most Positive Reactions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussions ordered by highest sum of positive reactions given to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions with Most Negative Reactions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Discussions ordered by highest sum of negative reactions given to them. This leaderboard will not be displayed if negative reactions are not in use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphs-3&#34;&gt;Graphs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of distinct members that viewed a page on the forum vs the number of visits by distinct users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sentiment Ratio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number of posts having a positive reaction vs the number of posts having a bad reaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visits per Active User&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
See Visits and Active users under the Traffic section for definitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Posts per Active User&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Average number of created posts grouped by active-users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average Comments per Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Average number of created comments grouped by discussions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Search</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/advanced-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/addons/advanced-search/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced Search adds robust options to Vanilla’s native search to help users hunt down specific content within your community. It is available on Corporate level plans and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better indexing of content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to apply filters to searches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-complete of results as the user types the search terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enabling-advanced-search&#34;&gt;Enabling Advanced Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable Advanced Search, you will need to enable the addon and then make a change to your base theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the addons page of the Dashboard, enable Advanced Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the Appearance section of the Dashboard, go to the Customer Theme page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the HTML tab, look for the following code  {searchbox}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change that code to  {searchbox_advanced}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-advanced-search&#34;&gt;Using Advanced Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating to &lt;code&gt;/search&lt;/code&gt; will bring you to a page with an expandable search bar. Clicking the arrow on the right side of the bar will show you all the extra parameters you have available for search:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.v-cdn.net/docs/search_expanded.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;You can search threads by title, author, and tags. You can narrow results down to a specific category, and choose what discussion types to search.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also link to &lt;code&gt;/search?adv=1&lt;/code&gt; to have these options already expanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, users will only see these options on the &lt;code&gt;/search&lt;/code&gt; page. To switch out the search bar on your homepage, simply change out &lt;code&gt;{searchbox}&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;{searchbox_advanced}&lt;/code&gt; in your custom theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced search also enables an autocomplete function that pulls results as you type.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.v-cdn.net/docs/search_autocomplete.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Autocompleted results based on a keyword&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for something very specific, there are some additional parameters you can use to help narrow down results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;“keyword phrase”&lt;/code&gt;: A phrase wrapped in quotes must occur in that order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;+keyword&lt;/code&gt;: The keyword must occur in the search result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-keyword&lt;/code&gt;: The keyword must not occur in the result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;excluding-content-from-search&#34;&gt;Excluding Content From Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normal viewing permissions apply to search results. Searching as a guest or member will not return results with content from moderation or administration sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archiving a category will prevent its content from coming up in the site-based search. Threads in archived categories are still indexed by search engines. You can use this setting to exclude old announcements or other irrelevant threads from search results without causing broken links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.vanillaforums.com/help/vanilla-forums-friday-theme-tip-advanced-search/&#34;&gt;Blog: Advanced Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gLLtlTsC4h8&#34;&gt;Video: Advanced Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Settings</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/advanced-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/forum-settings/advanced-settings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-settings&#34;&gt;Advanced Settings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following settings can be configured in the Dashboard under Forum Settings &amp;gt; Advanced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussions per page  (the number of discussions displayed on a page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments per page (the number of comments displayed on a page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing time limit (this can be used to prevent edits after a certain time period.  Some user  Roles and permissions will may override this limit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable checkboxes (this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appearance</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/appearance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;customizing-your-forum-s-appearance&#34;&gt;Customizing Your Forum&amp;rsquo;s Appearance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your community should have a unique look and feel to match your website, app or product.  The appearance section of your Dashboard lets you control how your community forum will look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-title-and-logo&#34;&gt;Site Title and Logo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Dashboard under Appearance &amp;gt; Banner you can set the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Home page title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banner title (what is displayed in the browser title bar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banner logo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile banner logo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favicon  (the small logo that appears on the browser tab)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share image (an image that is sometimes displayed when someone posts a link to your community to a social media site)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;homepage&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your Dashboard under Appearance &amp;gt; Homepage you can set the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default homepage view. Typically, the Discussions view is the best choice. If your community is very large, the Categories view might make more sense.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern vs table layout. A table layout looks more like traditional forums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;base-theme&#34;&gt;Base Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Appearance &amp;gt; Themes you can select a base theme for both desktop and mobile devices. All base themes can be further customized by modifying the HTML and overriding the CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;avatars&#34;&gt;Avatars&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Appearance &amp;gt; Avatars page lets you set a default avatar (profile picture).   You can also enable the Vanillicon plugin to create a unique avatar for each member or the Gravatar plugin to use members&amp;rsquo; Gravatars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pockets&#34;&gt;Pockets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pockets are placeholders where you can add snippets of HTML or Javascript. They are useful for placing ads or widgets throughout your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.vanillaforums.com/help/pockets-banner-ads/&#34;&gt;Using Pockets for Banner Ads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.vanillaforums.com/help/power-pockets-adding-custom-html-js-vanilla-forum/&#34;&gt;Video: Pockets: Adding Custom HTML and Javascript to Your Vanilla Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;customizing-theme-html-and-css&#34;&gt;Customizing Theme HTML and CSS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s base themes can be customized to match your website. More information can be found &lt;a href=&#34;custom-theme/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;professional-services&#34;&gt;Professional Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or resorces, Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s PS team can customize a theme to your specifications. Pls contact your Customer Success Manager for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Ranks over SSO</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/applying-ranks-over-sso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/ranks/applying-ranks-over-sso/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-ranks-over-sso&#34;&gt;Applying Ranks over SSO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new rank or edit an existing one, checking &amp;ldquo;Applied Manually&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now edit a user&amp;rsquo;s profile and select that Rank or apply it over SSO by adding a matching RankID or Rank_Name parameter to the callback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This only works if you have checked &amp;ldquo;Applied Manually&amp;rdquo; on the rank. Also make sure that no automatically-triggered Ranks have a higher level, or they will override when triggered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Badges</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/reputation/badges/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside class=&#34;cloudfeature&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;Learn More...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Badges are designed to reinforce desirable behaviors on a forum. They are not necessarily awards for the best or most of something, but rather signs that point the way to positive participation in a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;default-badges&#34;&gt;Default badges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s Badges addon automatically creates a wide variety of badges. Some relate to core forum functions (like commenting), and some are only triggered by using additional addons (like Reactions). Default badges are typically assigned to users automatically when certain conditions are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;badges-list&#34;&gt;Badges list&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All badges are listed in the Dashboard under &amp;ldquo;Badges&amp;rdquo;. This includes any badge ever created in your forum, regardless of whether it is currently active or achievable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;users-badges&#34;&gt;Users&amp;rsquo; badges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A list of a users&amp;rsquo; badges will display, by default, in the panel of their profile as a grid of badge images. Badges awarded incrementally (such as membership anniversaries) will &amp;ldquo;stack&amp;rdquo;, meaning only the highest-increment badge will show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;viewing-a-badge&#34;&gt;Viewing a badge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking a badge&amp;rsquo;s name in the badges list will take you to a public page describing the badge. Users can get to this page by clicking the badge in their profile. This page shows the most recent recipients of the badge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancellation</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside class=&#34;cloudfeature&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;Learn More...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-worst-day&#34;&gt;The Worst Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, it happens. On rare occassion, we need to go our separate ways. We hate to see any customer leave, but it&amp;rsquo;s important any cloud providers you use have a strong data ownership policy. Ours is pretty simple: &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s your data.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-your-data&#34;&gt;Getting your data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four custom components to any forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploaded files (avatars, images, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme or plugin done as a &lt;em&gt;customer-specific&lt;/em&gt; customization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, the only one we do not ever provide is the config. This is simply because it would not help you at all (useless data &amp;amp; incompatible anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only provide custom themes or plugins that you created yourself, or that we created from scratch on your behalf under contract. If you customized one of our &lt;em&gt;proprietary&lt;/em&gt; cloud themes via your Dashboard, we cannot assist with transitioning that theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide complete database backups and uploaded files. There is no charge for this, with the reasonable caveats explained below. However, your billing must be up to date without exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We require two business days notice to get a database backup (with exceptions). They are provided as a standard MySQL dump. No other format is provided, because this format lets you create any &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; format you want; it&amp;rsquo;s the master tape, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the exception: if your site exceeds any of the following limits, we may need up to a week to shedule your backup. We might be able to do it quicker, we&amp;rsquo;re just playing it safe here because it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of data to move around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 million users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 million discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 million comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barring your objection, we may truncate your activity or log tables because they&amp;rsquo;re not very helpful and can make the dump exponentially larger (and therefore more difficult for you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only provide one database dump per month. If you are leaving, we will make a one-time exception so that you can get an advanced copy for preparation. We can coordinate a final backup for a specific time of a weekday during the hours 10am-4pm Eastern time if requested. Doing so outside of those hours may cost a fee to schedule staff to be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;uploaded-files&#34;&gt;Uploaded files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We typically need two working days&amp;rsquo; notice to provide your uploaded files. For sites with exceptional amounts of files (in excess of 10GB) we may require a week&amp;rsquo;s notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please only request this once. We generally cannot coordinate a &amp;ldquo;final backup&amp;rdquo; of these files for a specific time (downloading from a CDN is very slow) unless it&amp;rsquo;s very small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source&#34;&gt;Open source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to continue using Vanilla on your own, there&amp;rsquo;s both good news and bad. The good news is that we don&amp;rsquo;t maintain a private fork of Vanilla. Therefore, your data will mostly work as-is without further data conversions. The bad news is it&amp;rsquo;s a little more complicated than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you may need to build the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vanilla/vanilla&#34;&gt;latest version&lt;/a&gt; of the code from GitHub (&lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch). Try the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.vanillaforums.com/addon/vanilla-core&#34;&gt;latest stable release&lt;/a&gt; of Vanilla first, but if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use Composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, not all cloud-based addons are open source. There are open source alternatives for some, but you may need to convert the data yourself (We &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; provide any cloud-based addon data in your database). One example of this is Badges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, you may need to do some manual work to make existing file uploads appear correctly. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to unzip what we send you into your &lt;code&gt;/uploads&lt;/code&gt; folder if you&amp;rsquo;re moving to open source. You may need to find and delete any instance of &lt;code&gt;cf:&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~cf/&lt;/code&gt; in file paths stored in the database (try &lt;code&gt;GDN_User.Photo&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GDN_Media.Path&lt;/code&gt;). These prefixes trigger a CDN lookup in our cloud environment. The open source default is the &lt;code&gt;/uploads&lt;/code&gt; folder (which you should not need to prepend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find additional help from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;volunteer community&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/&#34;&gt;developer docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;support&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not provide support for leaving the cloud beyond this document and delivering your data as promised. It&amp;rsquo;s a hard goodbye, but if you roll up your sleeves, we&amp;rsquo;re confident you&amp;rsquo;ll have the tools you need to build your own future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, never forget: We offer free migrations from Vanilla open source to cloud if you ever want to return.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>