<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016 on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/2016/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016 on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, VIP releases were every other month. Other customers received updates on an ad-hoc basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;december&#34;&gt;December&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add full IPv6 support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add and improve addon icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add meta tags for discussion links to generate Twitter cards (when added to tweets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add settings to Dashboard for category max display depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some padding to HTML tables in posts (improve legibility).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for our new CDN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add accessibility attributes to Customize Theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pager to log views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve category headings detection and table view support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve markup of category settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure password editing fields toggle appropriately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow removal of button from HTML email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore Theme Preview functionality (except for Mobile 2014).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default to secure cookies if &amp;ldquo;ForceSSL&amp;rdquo; is set and using HTTPS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip validating discussion title when a draft is saved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve markup and make further enhancements to Dashboard v3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict upload filename to be per post instead of by entire discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow uploading a Photo when creating a new category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid auto-scrolling to top when in comment embed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirm that user wants to delete images before deleting (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update documentation links for Social Connect addons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace &amp;ldquo;Hide Category&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;Mute Category&amp;rdquo; option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow new messages to accept a subject parameter (if enabled) via URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix delete message button (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix delete ban button (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix category depth calculation in subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix IP filtering on user management page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix heading categories sometimes being wrapped in an anchor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix dashboard pager next button when there are 0 results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the user photo in search.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix extra &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags in plain text emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where nav is cut off on category add/edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix wrong heading for &amp;ldquo;activity&amp;rdquo; on profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix activity notifications falsely flagging as sent when it was skipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix ICO transparency issue after upload (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix permission check for Change Log page to allow moderators (Moderation.Manage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix avatar cropping in profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jsConnect: Add warning to jsConnect dashboard when provider is in test mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jsConnect: [Security] Add content-type to callback endpoint to prevent potential XSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badges: Add badge name as alt text to badge images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badges: Add the ability to edit thresholds for some badges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix results percentage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix cancel button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Hide category dropdown when already inside a category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polls: Fix auto-selecting first child category in category dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q&amp;amp;A: Fix auto-selecting first child category in category dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Add inform message to Reactions enable toggle (in Dashboard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix RSS view when BestOf is configured as tiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix customizations reverting after database updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: [Security] Add missing CSRF protection on &amp;ldquo;react&amp;rdquo; endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Fix reactions popup possible overlap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Translate reaction names in navigation breadcrumbs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MailChimp: Fix issue with synchronizing lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile Extender: Fix checkbox display on registration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore: Fix failure to unignore user if their ignore privileges have been revoked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Fix search in groups when the category is not viewable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warnings &amp;amp; Notes: Fix extra line after quote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civil Tongue: Add support for groups and group events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salesforce: Remove from options on profile social connect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split/Merge: Make the System user the new discussion&amp;rsquo;s author when splitting comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAML: Allow SAML to accommodate differently-configured XML responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SimpleAPI: Fix situations where other addons could conflict with API endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;september&#34;&gt;September&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Dashboard! This changed every page in the moderator/admin backend, including all addon settings pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add navigation memory to the Dashboard. It will now preserve menu collapsing states &amp;amp; your page within each section between visits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &amp;ldquo;Flat Categories&amp;rdquo; feature and optional navigation module. This allows browsing hundreds of categories as an alphabetical directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve how categories are managed in the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categories now default to type &amp;ldquo;Nested&amp;rdquo; and must have a type assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add full recipients list to Badges. Click the &amp;ldquo;Given&amp;rdquo; number from &amp;ldquo;Badges&amp;rdquo; in the Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new &amp;ldquo;Post Numbering&amp;rdquo; addon (by request only, currently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add new &amp;ldquo;Role Tracker&amp;rdquo; addon (by request only, currently).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to convert discussions to &amp;ldquo;ideas&amp;rdquo; (if Ideation is enabled).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to configure warnings in Warnings &amp;amp; Notes addon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add redirects for Lithium and Ning community imports (Redirector addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for vBulletin 3 &amp;amp; 4 showthread.php?p={POSTID} URL redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow &amp;ldquo;Location&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Title&amp;rdquo; to be edited from User Edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Profile Extender&amp;rsquo;s handling of non-ASCII characters in field names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactored how we handle all requests (dispatcher).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update MailChimp addon to use v3 of their API and support MailChimp &amp;ldquo;groups&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Facebook addon to use versioned endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix &amp;ldquo;Mark All Viewed&amp;rdquo; endpoint to prevent accidental or malicious triggering and fix its redirect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Bootstrap3 theme color schemes &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sandstone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;SafeStyles&amp;rdquo; option (previously deprecated).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General addon code maintenance done on: Groups, Reactions, Ranks, Polls, SAMLSSO, and Badges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue with embedding where you could stay scrolled down when changing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add username validation to /message/add endpoint (when pre-filling &amp;ldquo;To:&amp;rdquo; field via URL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix conflict between Discussion Photos addon and Ideation addon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability for Smarty templates to access &lt;code&gt;isMobile&lt;/code&gt; function, &lt;code&gt;userAgentType&lt;/code&gt; function, &lt;code&gt;homepage_title&lt;/code&gt; function, and &lt;code&gt;Homepage&lt;/code&gt; (boolean variable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where default role settings weren&amp;rsquo;t transferred from old system correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add additional line break to welcome email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not wrap images in a div if they are already in an anchor to fix potential clicking issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix autocomplete dropdown display in modals with Bootstrap3 theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the post that a user was warned for in the email notification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not serve empty (or comment-only) CSS files from Custom Theme feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix photos&amp;rsquo; URL for /user/summary API endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix quotes that are done on a user with spaces in its name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;tabindex&lt;/code&gt; for comments, conversations, discussions (for keyboard navigation around page).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add announcements to discussions RSS (in posting order).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block adding banning rules that would HAL-9000 the entire crew, like &lt;code&gt;*.*&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the basic (not advanced, which had no issue) search pager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not revalidate username on edit if no change on user edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not send &lt;code&gt;noindex&lt;/code&gt; meta on error pages to prevent legit pages from being un-indexed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the priority of custom.css to be higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix log link showing when no log exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow &amp;ldquo;Unanswered Questions&amp;rdquo; page title to be translated (Q&amp;amp;A addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for alternate SAML document structures (SSO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enforce max tags limit on the front end and cleanup tag validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode slashes in usernames when creating profile links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow comment drafts to be orphaned (instead of removed) when their discussion is deleted and rework drafts view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unregister plugins immediately after it has been disabled instead of waiting until the next page request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide email preferences when email is disabled globally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide the RSS icon from categories that are type &amp;lsquo;Categories&amp;rsquo; since they contain no discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trim all control characters from discussion title (helps prevent broken or blank titles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix scenario where discussion title could be blank.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix user search to allow numeric usernames as long as it&amp;rsquo;s an exact match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Akismet will now validate your key before accepting it (Cloud customers do not require their own key; it is optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Akismet addon description and deprecate TypePad option (no longer offered by TypePad).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide Participated menu for guests (Participated addon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let welcome email fallback to HomepageTitle when the site&amp;rsquo;s name is not set properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off autocomplete on text fields when editing users in dashboard (to prevent accidental data insertion).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve how table layouts choose their column widths according to the content in them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Q&amp;amp;A and how it interacts with Subcommunities, especially displaying an Unanswered count per community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change H2s for H1s for a few edit profile pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve consistency in module (widget) titles (usually H4) so they are properly configurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add invited user data to user exports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix button height in Share This widget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add OAuth2 library to core product for building custom implementations more easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix potential duplicate rank promotion notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the priority order of the SimpleAPI plugin so Subcommunities does not interfere with API calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;july&#34;&gt;July&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New plugin: Role Tracker (aggregates discussions with posts by users in particular roles).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New plugin: Welcome Post (invites newly registered to start an intro discussion immediately).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade to Smarty 3 templating engine for custom themes. It&amp;rsquo;s a little bit stricter, faster, and more secure than Smarty 2 was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further improve scaling for large numbers of categories. Faster page loads!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to exclude moderators and/or admins from leaderboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move profile thumbnail editing to same page as photo uploading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenID: Prevent bad rendering when URL is invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t show Google+ login when enabled but not configured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for inline (async) forms for future Vanilla use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep attachments when a discussion becomes a comment via Split/Merge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically update CSRF token with async requests. This is so we can invalidate them more frequently in the future, improving our security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ideation page as a target for messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the categories page as a target for messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a limit on the page number in Best Of (it helps performance to not let pages go infinitely high).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix edge cases where notifications preferences would not display completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tighten security of Target parameter during sign in to disallow bad redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refresh the page after announcing a discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown: Allow starting lists without a newline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change how IP addresses are logged and allow IPv6 (no more 0.0.0.2 placeholder addresses appearing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the invite feature from the Getting Started page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove site logo from Deflector theme footer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Cyrillic character recognition in CivilTongueEx, allowing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Ideation crashing /discussions/promoted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix default translation of &amp;ldquo;Post Discussion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Fix &amp;ldquo;unanswered&amp;rdquo; status for discussions converted to questions by an admin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Add synchronize for subcommunities and default locale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix emoji menu not being properly dismissed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide &amp;ldquo;Dismiss&amp;rdquo; option on announcements from guests because it didn’t actually do anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add CSRF prevention and remove redirect from Mark All Viewed option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encode mail subject properly (UTF-8).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix broken reaction pagination on profile pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix emoji and mention from rendering inside WYSIWYG code blocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add $Homepage Smarty variable that is true/false depending on if you are on the homepage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix double encoding Open Graph title tag. This would have shown up as extra ampersands in Facebook shares and the like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Do not sync category permissions for an overridden role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hub: Add optional landing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to separate library for password hashing. We&amp;rsquo;re compartmentalizing some features like this to make maintenance easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We completed some very large projects to carefully rework several parts of our framework to get ready for API v2, but there&amp;rsquo;s no outward effect of this for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;may&#34;&gt;May&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrade to reCaptcha 2 (&amp;ldquo;NoCaptcha&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make &amp;ldquo;NBBC&amp;rdquo; our new BBCode parsing library by default (no more plugin).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability for SAML SSO to not be the default login method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow moving a discussion between subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for switching subcommunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve category scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make activities self-prune after 2 months to improve performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always redirect to the first page after saving a discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add analytics tracking for Q&amp;amp;A&amp;rsquo;s accepted answers (coming soon to analytics).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow censoring content in conversation message notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow censoring poll votes in comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix a number of edge cases where certain actions could block other actions without a page refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix condition where category announcements disappeared from recent discussions page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add caching for the default authentication provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve security in signin redirects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve use of &amp;lsquo;Alt&amp;rsquo; CSS class, which will be removed eventually (now redundant with current CSS specs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add option to configure a redirect after logout on Auth0 plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Triple-A and Bootstrap 3 themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue where Vimeo and Instagram embeds overflow out of the Best Of Tiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix where SplitMerge addon may be unable to save split discussion with &amp;ldquo;Html&amp;rdquo; format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix the love bug (various problems with &amp;lt; 3 in user-generated content).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent unneeded recurring updates in dashboard&amp;rsquo;s database updater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Gravatar&amp;rsquo;s use of system default avatar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add optional rating parameter to Gravatar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix GitHub signin and API permission issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix new discussion button showing in subcommunity when user has no permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the Photo field to be set in /profile/edit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only use CommentID for spam check if available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix incorrect permission being checked in some category management actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Simplify &amp;amp; fix event timezone handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make initial spoiler text the same colour as its background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix RSS title encoding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to capture a user&amp;rsquo;s time zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix LinkedIn &amp;ldquo;profile connect&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move Recaptcha into a plugin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add support for Instagram embeds in Mobile 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do more image optimizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Safari issue where back button wouldn&amp;rsquo;t refresh the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where people can quote a post and see uncensored content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove gender from user-facing elements like registration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevent &amp;ldquo;Messages&amp;rdquo; from being displayed when you do not have view permission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Return the correct number of questions for a subcommunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch YouTube links to https.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix mention issues including using an &amp;lsquo;@&amp;rsquo; in the middle of two words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix PNG compression issues in file uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix some minor issues that could make spoilers malfunction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a safety feature to avoid too-big database changes all at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow any user with moderate permission to add discussions and events in a group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix aggressive span stripping in the HTML purifier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;march&#34;&gt;March&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Ideation (vote on ideas) - Contact your CSM for more details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Microsoft Account SSO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: CAS SSO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Keyword Blocker (send posts with certain keywords to mod queue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Necro Posts (labels recently-revived discussions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: User Points Booster (allow awarding points for discussions or comments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New addon: Whitelist (provide an IP whitelist for site access)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML emails now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicants list is now asynchronous with improved UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoilers added as core feature with updated formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic bans (from Banning rules) can now be reversed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions will now always show on all devices, instead of on-hover for larger screens (&amp;ldquo;desktop&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign In form now auto-focuses on Username field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix newest comment data for zero-comment discussions in table view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post excerpts (as in search) now have a minimum length of 32 even if a double-return is found first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove line breaks in meta description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added events to support new analytics system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix styling of &amp;lsquo;/me&amp;rsquo; posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QnA: Allow users to accept their own answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reactions: Add an option to allow users to react to their own posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add advanced editor options to New Poll screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix plus signs in URLs, especially usernames / profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve SSO workflow for existing usernames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework discussion sorting and filtering architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add no-store header to profiles so read/unread status updates on Back button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pockets: fix repeating pockets between discussions, and enable on table view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subcommunities: Fix category dropdown filtering when in a subcommunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide editor toolbar when previewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix double-deletion of comment drafts when posting, which could cause a Javascript error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix scenario where Quotes could interfere with Spoilers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanillicons: Now defaults to v2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NBBC: Fix scenario that could break search results formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix opaque photo cropping box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix and unify logic for determining permission to edit a user&amp;rsquo;s photo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow quotes to be collapsed in reported posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow collapsing of quotes with alternate formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make even deeply-nested quotes minimally legible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update dropdown menu rendering in several places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update number formatting for discussion &amp;amp; comment counts on All Categories page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update stock themes for Ideation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups: Allow anyone who can edit an event to also delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;january&#34;&gt;January&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore no-store header to discussion &amp;amp; category lists (fixes &amp;ldquo;read&amp;rdquo; markers not updating on &amp;ldquo;Back&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved formatting of Vanilla Comments in certain input formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Smarty template parsing library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix an issue in draft saving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix spam deletion error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update Editor to use files&amp;rsquo; real names when downloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix RSS feed when table view is in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove deprecated form field name prefixing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more category data to VanillaPop emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update gifv embed to prefer WebM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various low-level fixes for PHP 7 compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix CSRF check when deleting a ban.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close open redirect &amp;amp; fix flood control in database updating endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve security in how Vimeo is embedded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Wistia embed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enforce POST data for several endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve theme compatibility with Groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically remove spaces around Banning rules to prevent bad data being entered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve image resizing to always use highest quality images possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Facebook SSO: retrieval of email address, avatar distortion, &amp;amp; name overwriting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &amp;ldquo;dashboard&amp;rdquo; namespace from several dashboard URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix several MySQL strict mode errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove livequery jQuery extension and all remaining uses of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove base64 encoding from all asynchronous requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow setting of avatar via API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow category permissions to be set via API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow certain configurations to be set depending on permission level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-add user count to the user list whenever possible based on size of table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give full formatting bar to Activity form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>