<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integrations on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/integrations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Integrations on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Facebook Connect allows users to sign in using their Facebook account. You must register your application with Facebook for this plugin to work.
How to set up Facebook Connect In order to set up Facebook Connect, you must create an &amp;ldquo;application&amp;rdquo; in Facebook at: https://developers.facebook.com/apps
Once your application has been set up, you must copy the &amp;ldquo;Application ID&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Application Secret&amp;rdquo; into your Facebook plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gigya Sign In</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/gigya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/gigya/</guid>
      <description>Gigya Sign In The Gigya Sign In adds the ability to sign to your community with Gigya Social Login. You will need to configure your site in your Gigya dashboard and then set up your login plugin on the Gigya plugins page before you can use the Gigya addon in Vanilla.
Setting up your site in Gigya  Instructions on setting up a a site in Gigya can be found in their site setup documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/integrations/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/integrations/github/</guid>
      <description>Github This plugin allows you to submit user discussion and comments as GitHub issues.
Setup Instructions If you already have a Github account, you need to enable API Access for this plugin to work.
 Create a new application in GitHub, and set the callback URL by appending /profile/githubconnect to the end of your forum’s URL. (If your forum is at example.com/forum, your callback URL would be http://example.com/forum/profile/githubconnect). Once your application has been set up, you must copy the ClientID and Secret into your Github plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Plus</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/googleplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/googleplus/</guid>
      <description>Google Plus The Google Plus Sign-In adds the ability to sign to your community with Google Plus. You will need to configure your site in Google API Console. This Google+ Video Tutorial also shows you how to set this up.
Setting up social login in Google Plus  Once you have enabled the Google+ Plugin in your Vanilla Dashboard, go to your API Console at Google. You will need to create a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/linkedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/linkedin/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn Linked In social sign in allows users to sign in using their LinkedIn account. You must register your application with LinkedIn for this addon to work.
How to Set up LinkedIn Social Sign in  Go to the LinkedIn Developer Network at https://www.linkedin.com/secure/developer/ Click Add New Application. When you create the application, you can choose what to enter in most fields, but you have to make sure you enter specific information for some fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Connect Plugins</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/</guid>
      <description>Social Connect Plugins Vanilla Forums integrates with a number of social applications that you can use as SSO solutions. Learn more about configuring these applications to work with your forum in this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/addons/social/twitter/</guid>
      <description>Twitter Twitter Connect allows users to sign in using their Twitter account. You must register your application with Twitter for this plugin to work.
Setting up social login in Twitter Connect  Register Vanilla with Twitter at: https://apps.twitter.com/app/new Set the Callback URL by appending /entry/twauthorize to the end of your forum’s URL. (If your forum is at example.com/forum, your Callback URL would be http://example.com/forum/entry/twauthorize). After registering, copy the &amp;ldquo;Consumer Key&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Consumer Secret&amp;rdquo; into your Twitter plugin settings page from your Vanilla dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>