<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saml on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>/tags/saml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saml on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="/tags/saml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SAML</title>
      <link>/help/features/sso/saml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help/features/sso/saml/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sso-with-saml-overview&#34;&gt;SSO with SAML: Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla has implemented the parts of the SAML 2.0 spec required for SSO. This is done by enabling the SAMLSSO addon, and configuring it via its Settings page (Dashboard -&amp;gt; Addons -&amp;gt; SAMLSSO -&amp;gt; Settings button).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAML accounts are mapped to existing forum accounts by &lt;strong&gt;email address&lt;/strong&gt;, or a new account is created if no match is found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s SAML mapping is as follows (the right value is the SAML key):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;UniqueID =&amp;gt; id
Name =&amp;gt; uid
Email =&amp;gt; mail
Photo =&amp;gt; photo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also accept a &lt;code&gt;roles&lt;/code&gt; field optionally. &lt;code&gt;Photo&lt;/code&gt; is likewise optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;UniqueID&lt;/code&gt; is whatever you&amp;rsquo;re using to absolutely uniquely identify the user on your side that will never change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Name&lt;/code&gt; is the username. We recommend keeping it within the normal rules (alphanumerics and underscores only, 50-character limit, must be unique) but we do not validate its formatting on our side over SSO because we don&amp;rsquo;t want to fail a login. It would just make @mentions impossible to use if it had spaces or special characters in it. However, in the case where there&amp;rsquo;s a duplicate name or none provided, it will send the user to a &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; page to provide a valid, unique username which will then also be validated for formatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t validate emails on our side either. In general, we are assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve done the data validation on your side and adding more would gum up the works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roles consist of a comma-separated list of exact name matches to existing roles on your forum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>