<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/categories/leaving/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="//docs.vanillaforums.com/categories/leaving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving the Cloud</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/leaving/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;aside class=&#34;cloudfeature&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/img/help/cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.com&#34;&gt;Learn More...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-worst-day&#34;&gt;The Worst Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, it happens. On rare occassion, we need to go our separate ways. We hate to see any customer leave, but it&amp;rsquo;s important any cloud providers you use have a strong data ownership policy. Ours is pretty simple: &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s your data.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-your-data&#34;&gt;Getting your data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four custom components to any forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uploaded files (avatars, images, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme or plugin done as a &lt;em&gt;customer-specific&lt;/em&gt; customization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Config&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these, the only one we do not ever provide is the config. This is simply because it would not help you at all (useless data &amp;amp; incompatible anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only provide custom themes or plugins that you created yourself, or that we created from scratch on your behalf under contract. If you customized one of our &lt;em&gt;proprietary&lt;/em&gt; cloud themes via your Dashboard, we cannot assist with transitioning that theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide complete database backups and uploaded files. There is no charge for this, with the reasonable caveats explained below. However, your billing must be up to date without exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We require two business days notice to get a database backup (with exceptions). They are provided as a standard MySQL dump. No other format is provided, because this format lets you create any &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; format you want; it&amp;rsquo;s the master tape, if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the exception: if your site exceeds any of the following limits, we may need up to a week to shedule your backup. We might be able to do it quicker, we&amp;rsquo;re just playing it safe here because it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of data to move around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 million users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 million discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 million comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barring your objection, we may truncate your activity or log tables because they&amp;rsquo;re not very helpful and can make the dump exponentially larger (and therefore more difficult for you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We only provide one database dump per month. If you are leaving, we will make a one-time exception so that you can get an advanced copy for preparation. We can coordinate a final backup for a specific time of a weekday during the hours 10am-4pm Eastern time if requested. Doing so outside of those hours may cost a fee to schedule staff to be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;uploaded-files&#34;&gt;Uploaded files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We typically need two working days&amp;rsquo; notice to provide your uploaded files. For sites with exceptional amounts of files (in excess of 10GB) we may require a week&amp;rsquo;s notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please only request this once. We generally cannot coordinate a &amp;ldquo;final backup&amp;rdquo; of these files for a specific time (downloading from a CDN is very slow) unless it&amp;rsquo;s very small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source&#34;&gt;Open source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to continue using Vanilla on your own, there&amp;rsquo;s both good news and bad. The good news is that we don&amp;rsquo;t maintain a private fork of Vanilla. Therefore, your data will mostly work as-is without further data conversions. The bad news is it&amp;rsquo;s a little more complicated than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you may need to build the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vanilla/vanilla&#34;&gt;latest version&lt;/a&gt; of the code from GitHub (&lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch). Try the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.org/addon/vanilla-core&#34;&gt;latest stable release&lt;/a&gt; of Vanilla first, but if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use Composer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, not all cloud-based addons are open source. There are open source alternatives for some, but you may need to convert the data yourself (We &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; provide any cloud-based addon data in your database). One example of this is Badges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, you may need to do some manual work to make existing file uploads appear correctly. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to unzip what we send you into your &lt;code&gt;/uploads&lt;/code&gt; folder if you&amp;rsquo;re moving to open source. You may need to find and delete any instance of &lt;code&gt;cf:&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~cf/&lt;/code&gt; in file paths stored in the database (try &lt;code&gt;GDN_User.Photo&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;GDN_Media.Path&lt;/code&gt;). These prefixes trigger a CDN lookup in our cloud environment. The open source default is the &lt;code&gt;/uploads&lt;/code&gt; folder (which you should not need to prepend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may find additional help from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vanillaforums.org/discussions&#34;&gt;volunteer community&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/&#34;&gt;developer docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;support&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not provide support for leaving the cloud beyond this document and delivering your data as promised. It&amp;rsquo;s a hard goodbye, but if you roll up your sleeves, we&amp;rsquo;re confident you&amp;rsquo;ll have the tools you need to build your own future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, never forget: We offer free migrations from Vanilla open source to cloud if you ever want to return.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>