<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Importing on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/importing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Importing on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="//docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/importing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building new porters</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/build/</guid>
      <description> Building a new porter file We don&amp;rsquo;t support your forum? Here are some tips for getting started rolling your own.
 Copy an existing class, like class.smf.php and rename it. Start simple. Get a working porter for users, categories, discussions, and comments before expanding its scope.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/</guid>
      <description>Importing to Vanilla Already have a community on another platform? Great! We have a tool called Vanilla Porter that can help you migrate from many other popular platforms.
Download Vanilla Porter
Vanilla Porter is a tool that you can upload to your current web server to run in your web browser. It exports any platform to a generic format that the &amp;ldquo;Import&amp;rdquo; option in your new Vanilla Forum can read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported platforms</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/support/</guid>
      <description>Supported platforms Migration tools are available for the following platforms. All migration tools minimally support users, categories, discussions, and comments. For a current per-platform, per-feature support list, see the Vanilla Porter.
PHP forums  Vanilla 1 phpBB 2-3 vBulletin 3-5 bbPress 1 SimplePress 1 Simple Machines 1-2 PunBB 1 IP.Board 3 XenForo Joomla Kunena Drupal Advanced Forum MyBB esoTalk Expression Engine  ASP / .NET forums Requires conversion to MySQL first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Porter</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/importing/porter/</guid>
      <description>Migrating a forum to Vanilla Vanilla Porter is the export tool for converting your legacy forum to Vanilla. The process is four steps:
 Export your old forum data to a special &amp;ldquo;Porter file&amp;rdquo;. Create a new Vanilla forum. Import the Porter file in Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s Dashboard. Verify &amp;amp; finalize your new forum.  Vanilla Porter requires a MySQL database and PHP 5.3+ with zlib support enabled.
Before migrating We recommend these best practices:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>