<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/configuration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Settings</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/banner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/banner/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;banner-settings&#34;&gt;Banner Settings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Banner Settings page you can control the following aspects of your forum:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homepage title: This is the title displayed on your home page. This title will also appear in search engines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site Description: This is the site description for your homepage. Other pages will have description generated by the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banner Title: This is the title will in your community&amp;rsquo;s banner, if you have not uploaded a banner image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banner Logo: This will replace the Banner Title. You have the freedom to use whatever size you want, but 250px x 50px is a great size that works nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Banner Logo: This allows you to add a small banner for the mobile theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favicon: This is the icon usually seen in the URL bar and when someone bookmarks a link from your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share Image: This is the image that will be included when content is shared on social networks (like Reddit or Google+) if no image is present in the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vanilla-configuration-files&#34;&gt;Vanilla configuration files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla uses a file-based configuration system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla is distributed with a file at &lt;code&gt;/conf/config-defaults.php&lt;/code&gt; which we will call &amp;ldquo;config-defaults&amp;rdquo;. After installation, a file is created at &lt;code&gt;/conf/config.php&lt;/code&gt; which we will call simply &amp;ldquo;config&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;config.php&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your config-defaults file should &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; be edited. It is overwritten during every upgrade. Sometimes future changes may depend on your default configuration being changed and this is the mechanism thru which it will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All configuration changes are to be exclusively made to your config.php file. We recommend periodically making a backup copy of your &lt;code&gt;config.php&lt;/code&gt; and storing it in a safe location (not on your web server).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;editing-configuration&#34;&gt;Editing configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;?php
// Config file entries look like this:
$Configuration[&#39;Area&#39;][&#39;FeatureSet&#39;][&#39;Setting&#39;] = &#39;Value&#39;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Config entires must render as valid PHP code, so the placement of quotes, brackets, and semicolons is extremely important. Line order does not matter, unless you accidentally duplicate values (which should be avoided). In that case, the last duplicate would take precedence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some scenarios for editing your config:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to change a config setting, so you simply change &amp;lsquo;Value&amp;rsquo; on 1 line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to change a default, so you copy a line from config-defaults into config, then modify its value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to add a new config value entirely, so you enter it using the format indicated above on a new line in the config.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;avoiding-accidental-overwrites&#34;&gt;Avoiding accidental overwrites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only open or copy your config for editing &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you have applied or saved your latest settings in the Dashboard, and wait until you are done editing to make further changes to your site. Saving your config will overwrite any changes you may have made elsewhere at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shorthand-references&#34;&gt;Shorthand references&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about config lines, we use the following shorthand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Area.FeatureSet.Setting = &#39;Value&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;?php
// The shorthand written using the full formatting
$Configuration[&#39;Area&#39;][&#39;FeatureSet&#39;][&#39;Setting&#39;] = &#39;Value&#39;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the above is written in instructions or comments, it is still to be formatted in the config according to the format shown earlier with brackets and quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Always double-check you have properly transcribed the name and value before saving.&lt;/aside&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dashboard&#34;&gt;Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Administration Panel, known as the Dashboard, provides access to the control features of your Vanilla Forum. Each Administration Panel is presented in sections, the header, the main navigation, the work area, and the footer. The top portion of all Panels, the header, is featured in a dark blue gradient. The header shows the name of your forum as a link to your forum&amp;rsquo;s main page, a profile link (shown as your user name), and Sign Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left side of the screen is the main navigation menu detailing each of the administrative functions you can perform. Within each major function, such as Appearance, a list of sub-menu items appear, certain sub-menu items may vary depending on what addons you have installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large area to the right of the screen is the work area. It is here the specific information relating to a particular navigation choice, such as adding a new post, is presented and collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in the footer, at the bottom of each Administration Panel also in a dark blue gradient, are links to Vanilla Forums, and Documentation. In addition, the version of Vanilla Forums you have installed can be found.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Settings</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/homepage/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;homepage&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Homepage settings allows you to change the default homepage of your community when they visit your site.  By default, Vanilla will use &amp;ldquo;Discussions&amp;rdquo; as your homepage, but you can change it to whatever you like.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messages</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/message/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;messages&#34;&gt;Messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messages can appear anywhere in your community, and can be used to inform your users of news and events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configuring-messages&#34;&gt;Configuring Messages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messages can be added to your forum by clicking on the Add Message button when on the Message page, and choosing the following
Message options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can determine on which page a Message will seen, for example just on the profile page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can add a Message to a specific category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You decide the position on the page the Message appears, for example below the sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 4 kinds of Messages available in Vanilla: Casual, Information, Alert and Warning. Each with a distinctive color you can modify in your CSS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Config</title>
      <link>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration/using/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-to-use-the-config&#34;&gt;When to use the config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the config for saving settings in your theme or plugin. You should only save small amounts of data to the config, and it should not be data that is changed frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have large quantities of data or data that is written frequently, consider using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/framework/database&#34;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-from-config&#34;&gt;Reading from config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; function is the appropriate shortcut for reading from the config. The first parameter is the name of the config value in &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.vanillaforums.com/developer/configuration&#34;&gt;dot notation&lt;/a&gt;. The second is an optional default value to return if requested config setting is not defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:
&lt;code&gt;$Value = c(&#39;Name.Of.Setting&#39;, &#39;DefaultValue&#39;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can call a partial config key to get an array of all values below it in dot notation. For instance, say this was in your config:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;$Configuration[&#39;Example&#39;][&#39;Settings&#39;][&#39;A&#39;] = 1;
$Configuration[&#39;Example&#39;][&#39;Settings&#39;][&#39;B&#39;] = 2;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now calling &lt;code&gt;c(&#39;Examples.Settings&#39;);&lt;/code&gt; will return &lt;code&gt;array(&#39;A&#39;=&amp;gt;1, &#39;B&#39;=&amp;gt;2)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-to-config&#34;&gt;Writing to config&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save to the config with the &lt;code&gt;SaveToConfig&lt;/code&gt; function. It takes the name of the config value, a new value to associate with it, and an optional options array. In the options array, you can pass the key &lt;code&gt;Save&lt;/code&gt; with the value &lt;code&gt;FALSE&lt;/code&gt; to make the config change only apply for this pageload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change a config setting permanently: &lt;code&gt;SaveToConfig(&#39;Name.Of.Setting&#39;, &#39;NewValue&#39;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change a config setting only for this pageload: &lt;code&gt;SaveToConfig(&#39;Name.Of.Setting&#39;, &#39;NewValue&#39;, array(&#39;Save&#39; =&amp;gt; FALSE));&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply passing the value &lt;code&gt;FALSE&lt;/code&gt; in place of the options array has the same effect as passing &lt;code&gt;array(&#39;Save&#39; =&amp;gt; FALSE)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;Do not used numeric-key arrays as config values. Associative arrays are fine.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration-module&#34;&gt;Configuration module&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve created a shortcut for making simple settings pages using the &lt;code&gt;ConfigurationModule&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration module can be instantiated and rendered from any plugin. You &lt;code&gt;Initialize&lt;/code&gt; it with an array of config values, each of which has its own array of properties to define it (type of field, label, default, etc). See &lt;code&gt;applications/dashboard/modules/class.configurationmodule.php&lt;/code&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the Akismet plugin uses the ConfigurationModule to build a simple settings page consisting of a text field and a dropdown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;$Cf = new ConfigurationModule($Sender);
$Cf-&amp;gt;Initialize(array(
    &#39;Plugins.Akismet.Key&#39; =&amp;gt; [&#39;Description&#39; =&amp;gt; $KeyDesc],
    &#39;Plugins.Akismet.Server&#39; =&amp;gt; [
        &#39;Description&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;You can use either Akismet or TypePad antispam.&#39;, 
        &#39;Control&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;DropDown&#39;, &#39;Items&#39; =&amp;gt; [
            &#39;&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;Aksimet&#39;, 
            &#39;api.antispam.typepad.com&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;TypePad&#39;, 
            &#39;DefaultValue&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;&#39;
        ]
    ]
));
$Cf-&amp;gt;RenderAll();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all there is to it - no custom view is involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>