<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/configuration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Banner Settings</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/banner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/banner/</guid>
      <description>Banner Settings On the Banner Settings page you can control the following aspects of your forum:
 Homepage title: This is the title displayed on your home page. This title will also appear in search engines. Site Description: This is the site description for your homepage. Other pages will have description generated by the content. Banner Title: This is the title will in your community&amp;rsquo;s banner, if you have not uploaded a banner image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Vanilla configuration files Vanilla uses a file-based configuration system.
Vanilla is distributed with a file at /conf/config-defaults.php which we will call &amp;ldquo;config-defaults&amp;rdquo;. After installation, a file is created at /conf/config.php which we will call simply &amp;ldquo;config&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;config.php&amp;rdquo;.
Your config-defaults file should never be edited. It is overwritten during every upgrade. Sometimes future changes may depend on your default configuration being changed and this is the mechanism thru which it will happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard The Administration Panel, known as the Dashboard, provides access to the control features of your Vanilla Forum. Each Administration Panel is presented in sections, the header, the main navigation, the work area, and the footer. The top portion of all Panels, the header, is featured in a dark blue gradient. The header shows the name of your forum as a link to your forum&amp;rsquo;s main page, a profile link (shown as your user name), and Sign Out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Settings</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/homepage/</guid>
      <description>Homepage The Homepage settings allows you to change the default homepage of your community when they visit your site. By default, Vanilla will use &amp;ldquo;Discussions&amp;rdquo; as your homepage, but you can change it to whatever you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messages</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/message/</guid>
      <description>Messages Messages can appear anywhere in your community, and can be used to inform your users of news and events.
Configuring Messages Messages can be added to your forum by clicking on the Add Message button when on the Message page, and choosing the following Message options:
 You can determine on which page a Message will seen, for example just on the profile page. You can add a Message to a specific category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Config</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/developer/configuration/using/</guid>
      <description>When to use the config Use the config for saving settings in your theme or plugin. You should only save small amounts of data to the config, and it should not be data that is changed frequently.
If you have large quantities of data or data that is written frequently, consider using the database instead.
Reading from config The c function is the appropriate shortcut for reading from the config.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>