<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Releases on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Releases on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:8081/tags/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2016/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes In 2016, VIP releases were every other month. Other customers received updates on an ad-hoc basis.
December  Add full IPv6 support. Add and improve addon icons. Add meta tags for discussion links to generate Twitter cards (when added to tweets). Add settings to Dashboard for category max display depth. Add some padding to HTML tables in posts (improve legibility). Add support for our new CDN. Add accessibility attributes to Customize Theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/2017/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes Quarterly VIP releases contain all numbered releases within said quarter.
Sometimes bug fixes are backported to the current release, meaning they show up in production earlier than the date noted.
Q2 release 6 (Thursday, June 29)  Improve load time of Vanilla Statistics dashboard summaries. Triple-A theme: Added missing icons for Reactions. Dashboard: Font tweaks for right panel. Dashboard: Fix inaccurate toggle position for embedding URLs in Posting Settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes (Cloud)</title>
      <link>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://127.0.0.1:8081/help/releases/</guid>
      <description>Cloud release schedule Our customers on VIP plans receive a product update once per quarter with new features, fixes, and enhancements. We coordinate these releases with our customers and provide custom QA or custom scheduling as required.
Customers with a success manager receive updates approximately every other week at a fixed time which is not pre-announced. Other plan levels and all staging sites may receive these updates on an ad-hoc basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>