<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Vanilla Forums Documentation</title>
    <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Vanilla Forums Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="//docs.vanillaforums.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2016/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes In 2016, VIP releases were every other month. Other customers received updates on an ad-hoc basis.
December  Add full IPv6 support. Add and improve addon icons. Add meta tags for discussion links to generate Twitter cards (when added to tweets). Add settings to Dashboard for category max display depth. Add some padding to HTML tables in posts (improve legibility). Add support for our new CDN. Add accessibility attributes to Customize Theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Cloud Releases</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/2017/</guid>
      <description>Release Notes Quarterly VIP releases contain all numbered releases within said quarter.
Sometimes bug fixes are backported to the current release, meaning they show up in production earlier than the date noted.
Q2 release 6 (Thursday, June 29)  Improve load time of Vanilla Statistics dashboard summaries. Triple-A theme: Added missing icons for Reactions. Dashboard: Font tweaks for right panel. Dashboard: Fix inaccurate toggle position for embedding URLs in Posting Settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Repository</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/repository/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Shared Private Repository Our VIP plans come with the option to open a private code repository that you share with the Vanilla Forums team on GitHub. This allows your developers to view and contribute to your custom features and theme.
Setup Your customer success manager will provide you with this repository. Please allow the Vanilla team to organize its structure appropriately and name files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Support</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/developer-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/developer-support/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Developer Support VIP plans include developer support, offered for a fixed period of time for a fixed number of individuals in your organization. During that time, those folks can reach out directly to Vanilla developers for advanced assistance in setting up embedding, single sign-on, theming, and appropriate addons &amp;amp; settings.
We will continue to assist you with our outstanding professional support even after your developer support ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/logging/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Advanced logging Additional logging is available on our highest-tier plans for an additional fee to cover the additional load &amp;amp; performance hit incurred by more verbose logs.
The logs are available via a Dashboard page under &amp;ldquo;Event Log&amp;rdquo;. They can be filtered by date range, event name, and severity. Sorting is chronological or reverse-chronological.
Events We are currently able to log the following additional events for auditing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/migration/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Overview Vanilla offers full, professional migration services from nearly any platform imaginable. If you provide the data, we&amp;rsquo;ll figure out how to make it work in Vanilla.
The process below assumes you will provide a database dump. We also perform API-based migrations from cloud services when that is necessary and possible. Talk to your account representative if you require a different type of migration like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Multisite management Vanilla&amp;rsquo;s cloud solution offers a number of configuration settings for enterprise-grade deployments.
Deployment Types Single Community This is a classic forum setup. It is the equivalent of 1 installation of forum software. It can have any number of categories (what other products call “topic areas” or “forums/subforums”) arranged in a hierarchy. Each Single Community needs a domain or subdomain assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multisite Sync</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/multisite/sync/</guid>
      <description>Hub Sync The hub has the ability to synchronize/push some configuration/data on the nodes. This allows an administrator to, for example, create a category on the hub and sync it to all the nodes. If the category is renamed or deleted at a later time hub it would be synchronized to the nodes again.
What can be synced?  A predefined set of configuration. This needs to be set up by a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premium Services</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Cloud Services Overview This section details services and processes that are only offered on certain plan levels. It includes workflows between Vanilla Forums and our clients, suggestions for getting the most out of your services, and expectations for how services will be delivered and communicated.
If you are a cloud client and have any questions, please contact support, your account representative, or your customer success manager if one has been assigned to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes (Cloud)</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/releases/</guid>
      <description>Cloud release schedule Our customers on VIP plans receive a product update once per quarter with new features, fixes, and enhancements. We coordinate these releases with our customers and provide custom QA or custom scheduling as required.
Customers with a success manager receive updates approximately every other week at a fixed time which is not pre-announced. Other plan levels and all staging sites may receive these updates on an ad-hoc basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staging Site</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/staging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/staging/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Staging Site Overview For higher plan levels, we provide a separate staging forum. You can use this account for testing addons, features, and theme changes before they reach your production site. Your customer success manager will provide this account for you upon request.
Test data We do not typically use your staging forum as the destination for your test migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support</title>
      <link>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//docs.vanillaforums.com/help/cloud/support/</guid>
      <description>This feature is only available on Vanilla Cloud Learn More...  Cloud Support We provide professional support exclusively for our cloud clients. Because of this, we require the forum owner to request support, or to specifically authorize other users to receive support.
Support is available by:
 Using the &amp;ldquo;Support&amp;rdquo; form in your Dashboard. Visiting the official support forum at https://support.vanillaforums.com. Sign in with the same email you used to register for cloud hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>